"Points West" by Steve Lopez.
“指向西部”史蒂夫・洛佩兹著
A construction foreman in Griffith Park heard the crash.
格里菲斯公园的一个工地工头听到了撞击声
Hey!
嘿！
He saw a cyclist cartwheel off his bike
他看到一个骑自行车的从车上翻了下来
and slam face-first into the unforgiving asphalt of Riverside Drive.
并且把脸摔进了湖边路那不可饶恕的沥青里
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
早上好，女士们先生们
As we begin our descent into Los Angeles,
我们即将降落在洛杉矶了
we ask that you please be sure that your seatbelts are fastened...
请大家确保扣上你们的安全带
A 911 call brought out the troops from Fire Station 76.
一通911的电话让第76消防站的队员出动了
- What happened? - You had an accident.
- 怎么回事？ - 你出车祸了
- Do you know what happened? - No shit, I had an accident. What?
- 你还记得事情的经过吗？ - 不，该死的，我出车祸了，怎么回事？
I don't remember any of this, nor do I recall the cause of the spill.
我完全记不起来了 连让我翻车的原因都不记得
- Our batteries are off. - I've been in here six hours now, and...
- 我们的电池没电了 - 我到这里已经6个小时，而且…
Listen to me. Wait a minute. We're ready to go...
听我说，请等等 我们正准备去…
Hypochondriac.
忧郁症
OR 2.
或者2号
County-USC was the closest emergency room,
南加州大学郡立医院是最近的医院了
and I quickly realized
而我很快意识到…
that if you find yourself there
如果你发现自己身在此处…
with nothing more than a bump on the head,
而身体除了头上的包之外都安然无恙的话…
you are one lucky Angeleno.
那你就是一位幸运的洛杉矶人了
Wow.
哇
Ready.
好了
I'm not entirely comfortable with this.
我在这玩意儿里面很不舒服
Thank you.
多谢
You have no new messages.
你有“0”条新信息
Okay.
好的
Really?
真的？
Doctors told me to expect up to four weeks of disorientation.
医生告诉我预计会有最长持续4周的 定向力障碍
Christ. All right.
上帝，好了
I'm not asking for sympathy. I just want you to know, I just...
我不是要你同情我，我只是要你知道，我…
I'm not asking for sympathy.
我不是要你同情我…
I just want you to understand what's going on
我只是想要你明白，这是怎么回事
if I start writing about what a bang-up job
如果我要为施瓦辛格州长的工作…
Governor Schwarzenegger's doing.
写篇赞美辞的话…
S-C-H-W-A-R-Z... Scratch that.
施瓦…名字真长
Pass¨¦. Lacks context.
以上忽略，缺乏下文
Right. So the question is...
对，所以问题就是…
Hey, Tommy.
嘿，汤米
Theoretically could I, seeing as how the Governor has retired
理论上，既然施瓦辛格州长已经从…
his position at the muscle magazine, could I interview him?
健美杂志模特岗位上退役了 那我能采访他吗？
Right. And will my non-Teutonic lineage be an issue?
对，那我的非条顿血统会有问题吗？
See, no, that's... That's... It gets to be funny. It's just an article.
看，不是，那是… 那是会有趣的，那只是一篇文章
Do I need to have been on steroids for a long time to even apply?
我是不是需要长期服用类固醇药物 才有机会申请？
Good.
好
Gail, I like the "attention must be paid" reference.
盖尔，我喜欢那场“必须引起关注”的文章
I might move it down a paragraph, though.
但我可能会把它移下一段
Thanks. I'm getting you a new desk.
谢谢，我要给你弄张新桌子
Good morning, gentlemen.
早上好，先生们
- Thanks. - Hey, guys. Check it out.
- 谢谢 - 嘿，大家伙，看看这个
I got a study here that says the number of Americans under 35
一家研究室说35岁以下的美国人中…
who read a newspaper is now down to 40./...
报纸读者的比率下降到了40%
- Forty? - Forty.
- 40？ - 40
And the group we're losing mostly are college-educated women.
而我们正在失去的读者群 绝大部分是受过高等教育的女性
- Pull my finger. - Jesus Christ.
- 拉拉我的手指 - 耶稣基督啊
Hey, honey.
嘿，甜心
"Welcome back, Steve." That would have been nice.
“欢迎回归，史蒂夫” 说这句话就很不错
Thank you. You know, when Lopez and I started out together...
多谢，知道吗，当洛佩兹和我认识的时候…
You had to walk 20 miles to school in the snow with no shoes?
你们不得不在大雪里光着脚 步行20里到学校去？
...people cared about what went on in the world.
人们对于时事非常关心
- Am I right, Steve? I mean, Christ. - Back when people cared.
- 我说的对吗，史蒂夫？我说，天啊 - 在那时你就是对的
We're at war, and the only thing that sells papers
我们在打仗，而唯一让报纸好卖的东西是…
is a Lindsay Lohan cooch shot.
林赛・萝涵的热舞艳照
Jesus, did someone actually run that in print?
天啊，真的有人把这登报了吗？
- I thought that was just on the Web. - All right, all right.
- 我以为这只是在网络上流传 - 好吧，好吧
- All I am saying is... - I didn't see that.
- 我要说的是… - 我没看到有这东西
...that if you run an excellent, if I do say so myself,
这不是我本人说的 如果你作了非常棒的一篇头版文章…
front-page piece about how corporate America is profiting from this war,
内容是关于全美国是如何在战争中受益的…
and the only reader response you get is on two hands...
而你能得到的读者反应就仅有 “摊开双手的不解状”
- Meanwhile... - That was a good piece, by the way.
- 同时… - 顺带说句，那报道不错
- Fine. Thanks. You read it? - I read that.
- 是不错，谢谢，你读过了？ - 我读过了
- Did you really? - I didn't read it, but I loved it, Curt.
- 真读过了？ - 我没读，但我喜欢，科特
Meanwhile, Lopez here scrapes his forehead,
同时，这位洛佩兹摔伤了额头…
and gets, what, I'm guessing about 75 e-mails
然后得到了什么？我猜约有75封电邮
from readers worried about his safety?
全都来自担心他安危的读者的
- I chased this piece. - Then I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 我跟进这篇报道的… - 那我非常抱歉，非常抱歉
There is something very wrong in this world.
这世界非常非常有问题
Newsflash, something wrong with the world.
新闻简报：这世界出问题了
Yeah. Your face hurts my feelings, Steve.
是啊，你的脸让我难受，史蒂夫
That's harassment.
那太不好意思了
- Mary? - An environmental group studying...
- 玛丽？ - 一个环保小组，研究…
- Please. ...chemical contaminants
- 拜托 - 残留在人体内的…
- in people's bodies. - I literally... No.
- 化学污染物的 - 我简直…不
- Give some blood and write about it. - Let me check my e-mails.
- 给他们些血化验然后写篇东西 - 让我看看我的电邮
I think it would be a good idea for you.
我觉得这对你来说是个好主意
I'm glad you feel that way. I just did that.
我很高兴你这样想，我刚出过血
What do you think?
你觉得怎样？
The thought in my mind is, "No, thank you."
我内心的想法是：“不了，谢谢你”
It was funny. People love it when you bleed.
会很有趣的，所有人都喜欢看到你流血
- Readers. - Busted.
- 说的是读者 - 说漏嘴了吧
What is that? What do you call that, what you just did?
什么意思？这么说叫什么？ 刚才你怎么回事？
- Transference. - Freud.
- 移情作用 - 弗洛伊德的
Freud. Thank you. No.
弗洛伊德的，谢谢你，不
Sorry about the face.
你的脸伤我很遗憾
- I hate needles. - So use it.
- 我讨厌缝针 - 那就多用针
Originally used as a camp by settlers
最初是开拓者的宿营地
outside of what was then the village of Los Angeles,
这里外面就是当时的洛杉矶村
it was called La Plaza Abaja, or the Lower Plaza.
它被称作阿巴哈广场，或者低地广场
Stevie Wonder fan?
史蒂夫・汪达歌迷吗？ （史蒂夫・汪达是盲人歌手、音乐创作人）
My Cherie Amour is the song of my life.
“我亲爱的爱人”是我一生的挚爱 （这首歌是史蒂夫・汪达的代表作之一）
Signed, Sealed, Delivered.
“落款、封信、寄走” （也是史蒂夫・汪达的歌）
But you really shouldn't write on a violin like that
但是不应该为小提琴写这样的歌
because you have to treat a violin like a child, you have to protect it.
因为你应该像对待孩子一样对待小提琴 你应该保护它
You only got two strings.
你的琴只有两根弦
All I want to do is play music, and here's the problem
我想做的事情只有拉琴，而这就是…
that I'm having right here.
我现在最大的问题
This one's gone, this one's gone, this little one's out of commission.
这根断了，这根断了，这根细的走调了
But you get that in Cleveland public schools.
但你在克里夫兰公立学校里能得到这些东西
A lot of military statues in Cleveland.
克里夫兰有很多军事塑像
- A very military-oriented city. - Is that where you're from?
- 一座很具有军事导向性的城市 - 你就是从那来的吗？
You're not gonna get musicians on parade there.
在那边的巡游里你是看不到音乐家的
You got Severance Hall there. You have The Music Settlement.
那有断离大厅，有移民音乐学校
Ohio State University.
就在俄亥俄州立大学
Whereas in Los Angeles, you have Los Angeles PD, you have LA Times,
而在洛杉矶，这有洛城警局，有洛杉矶时报
you have Los Angeles Lakers.
有洛杉矶湖人
Those are armies, too. Military regimentation, experimentation,
这也有军队，有军事管辖区，军事试验
Roman gable, Roman Catholicism, Colonel Sanders,
罗马式边墙，罗马天主教 桑德斯上校（创建肯德基KFC那位）
- but this guy right here is... - Colonel Sanders.
- 但眼前的这家伙相当于… - 桑德斯上校
...the quarterback with the orchestra.
管弦乐队里的四分卫
Now the cello could back this guy with the same moves,
然后大提琴能以同样的奏法来给它做衬音
but the cello can't be concert master.
但是大提琴不能做音乐会的主音
No. He leads out, this was Itzhak Perlman, Jascha Heifetz.
不，他能领音 这是伊扎克・帕尔曼、雅沙・海飞兹 （二人均为小提琴演奏家）
You can't play music in the winter in Cleveland
你不能在克里夫兰的冬天里拉琴
because of the ice and the snow.
因为都是冰和雪
That's why I prefer Los Angeles to Beethoven City,
这就是我把洛杉矶叫做贝多芬之城的原因
because it never rains in Southern California,
因为南加州从来不下雨
and if it does, all I have to do is just go in the tunnel,
如果下雨了，我须要做的仅仅是走到隧道里
I could play to my heart's content.
我可以尽情地拉琴
I'm flabbergasted about the statue. Aren't you flabbergasted about this?
这尊塑像让我惊叹，难道你不是吗？
- Anyway, nice to meet you. - Do you have any idea how it got here?
- 不管怎样，很高兴见到你 - 你知道它怎么到这来的吗？
- No. - Maybe they dropped it off late at night.
- 不 - 可能他们在深夜把它运过来的
'Cause it's just astonishing to sit here for hours and just... Just gaze at it.
因为就这么坐着，看着它，就很让人惊叹了
- It... It just blows me away. - No idea.
- 它就这么让我叹服了 - 不知道呢
It really blows me away
这真的让我叹服了
that someone as great as Beethoven was the leader of Los Angeles.
因为和贝多芬一样的伟人是洛杉矶的领袖
Yeah.
是啊
I'm Steve Lopez, LA Times.
我是史蒂夫・洛佩兹，洛杉矶时报的
- Lopez, L-O-P-E-Z? - Yeah.
- 洛佩兹，L-O-P-E-Z？ - 是的
Lopez, Los Angeles Times. Mr. Lopez.
洛佩兹，洛杉矶时报，洛佩兹先生
- What's your name? - Lopez.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 洛佩兹
Nathaniel Anthony Ayers Junior.
纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世
N-A-T-H-A-N-l-E-L A-N-T-H-O-N-Y
N-A-T-H-A-N-I-E-L  A-N-T-H-O-N-Y
A-Y-E-R-S J-U-N-l-O-R.
A-Y-E-R-S  J-U-N-I-O-R
Or J-R-period.
或者“JR句号”就行
I apologize for my appearance. I've had a few setbacks.
我为我的样子道歉，我遇到了些挫折
Me, too.
我也一样
Who are Nancy, Paul, and Craig?
南希、保罗和克雷格都是谁？
Those were my classmates at Juilliard.
那些是我在朱利亚德学校的同学
Good afternoon, Juilliard School.
下午好，朱利亚德学校
Registrar's office, please.
请转注册办公室
What's up?
怎么了？
It's highly classified. I can't tell you.
高度机密，我不能说
- How many? - More than we can afford to lose.
- 要炒多少？ - 比我们能失去的要多
Evidently, it goes like this.
显然，事情是这样的
Stock price sinks, we lose reporters.
股价跌，我们失去一批通讯员
Stock price sinks more, we lose more reporters.
股票再跌，我们再失去一批通讯员
That won't produce more or less...
那样不会或多或少地产生…
Hi, this is Steve Lopez from the LA Times. I'm calling to enquire
嗨，我是洛杉矶时报的史蒂夫・洛佩兹 我想询问一下…
as to whether a Nathaniel Anthony Ayers attended your school.
是否有个叫纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯的人 就读过你们学校？
A-Y-E-R-S. I'm sorry.
A-Y-E-R-S 我很抱歉
Freaking child lock.
讨厌的片盘锁
- How is our son, by the way? - He's good.
- 对了，我们儿子怎样了？ - 他很好
He likes his classes. He likes his pre-gay roommate.
他喜欢上他的课 他喜欢那个有同性恋倾向的室友
You should call him.
你应该给他电话
- I call him. - Is a lie.
- 我打过了 - 说谎
I call him. He doesn't call me back.
我打过了，他没有回电
- He calls me back. - Mary...
- 他给我回电了 - 玛丽
- Just try again. - Yes, Mary.
- 再打一次 - 好的，玛丽
- Yes, Mary. - Yes. Yes, Steve.
- 好的，玛丽 - 好，好，史蒂夫
- I gotta take this call. - Great.
- 我一定要接这通电话 - 好极了
- Because I don't have a story. Hello? - Call him.
- 因为我没有东西可写了，你好？ - 给他电话
I'm sorry, we have no record
很抱歉，记录里没有…
of a Nathaniel Anthony Ayers ever attending Juilliard.
纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯的就读记录
Really?
真的？
But then I don't have a story.
这样我就没有文章可写了
Thanks for checking.
多谢协查
I'm not doing the blood thing.
我不做血检那玩意儿
I got too many other good ideas.
（拉小提琴的家伙） 我有太多其他的素材了
My dad is gonna freak when he finds out I met you.
我爸要知道我见到你本人会高兴坏的
He loves your column.
他爱死了你的专栏
What about you?
那你呢？
- Well, I don't really read the newspaper. - Sure.
- 呃，我其实不大读报纸 - 当然
But when I do...
不过，我看报的同时…
Hey! Those aren't all for me, are they?
嘿！这些不是都给我的吧？
I'm also going to need a clump of hair and some urine.
我还需要你给我一团头发和一些尿液
That's easy.
那些简单
- All right. - Okay.
- 好吧 - 好的
Make a fist for me.
握拳吧
Come on.
来吧
Crap.
靠
- Lopez. - Mr. Lopez?
- 洛佩兹 - 洛佩兹先生？
Yeah, can you just hold on one second?
是的，你能等我一会儿吗？
I'm having a little technical difficulty here.
我手头上有点技术难题
This is Rosie Delgado from the Juilliard School.
我是朱利亚德学校的罗西・德尔加多
Mr. Lopez?
洛佩兹先生？
Yes. Please continue.
在，请继续
After we spoke yesterday, I realized I only checked our graduates.
昨天挂电话后 我突然想起我只查了毕业名单
So I looked in our matriculates, and there he was.
所以我查了查录取名单，然后找到他了
Nathaniel Anthony Ayers enrolled in 1970
纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯于1970年入学
and he dropped out toward the end of his second year.
然后在第二学年的末尾退学了
Thank you.
谢谢你
"Points West" by Steve Lopez. Nathaniel was shy in our first encounter.
“指向西部”，史蒂夫・洛佩兹著 纳杉尼尔在我们初次见面时有些腼腆
He stepped back... He backed away.
他后退了，退却了
He... Nathaniel is... Is what?
他，纳杉尼尔，会是什么？
Nathaniel is... A great column is what Nathaniel is.
纳杉尼尔会是一个极佳的专栏素材
Nathaniel is missing.
纳沙尼尔失踪了
Son of a bitch.
混蛋
- Raccoons. - Oh, yeah?
- 是浣熊 - 噢，是吗？
- That's the culprit. - Oh, boy.
- 犯人就是它们 - 噢，天啊
What are they doing? They eat the grass?
它们要干什么？吃草吗？
No, they eat the worms in the grass.
不，它们吃草丛里的虫子
They eat the worms in the grass?
它们吃草里的虫？
Yeah, we had them. It's a God-awful mess.
是啊，我们的草皮里有虫子 真是极度的一团糟
- Wanna know how I got rid of them? - Yes.
- 想知道我怎么赶走它们的吗？ - 当然
Coyote urine.
郊狼尿
- Wow. Coyote urine? - Seriously. In powdered form.
- 哇，郊狼尿？ - 真的，粉末装的
- Remarkable. - It's a whole industry, you know.
- 真不寻常 - 这是一套完整的产业，知道吗？
Funny.
有趣
- Hey, I'm Neil, by the way. - Okay.
- 嘿，对了，我叫尼尔 - 好的
Anxiety, restlessness, euphoria. If you're experiencing...
“焦虑、烦躁、莫名愉快等 如果你有以上症状…”
I would spend every night tossing and turning...
“我会每晚都摇摆和旋转…”
Wow. Okay, and what is the proper method of application?
哇，好吧，恰当的使用方法是什么？
Should I sprinkle it in the yard?
我该把它撒在院子里吗？
First, you wanna dilute the urine powder in water.
首先，你想要用水稀释尿精粉
- Wait, I want to? - Well, maybe I should say "have to."
- 等等，我想要？ - 呃，或者我该说“你必须要”
And then you're gonna have to hang the liquid from trees in plastic bags.
然后你须要用塑料袋装起尿液挂在树上
So, people are doing this all over Southern California?
那么，南加州的人都用这个？
Oh, yes, sir. Last month, I sold some to Paula Abdul.
没错，先生 上个月，宝拉・阿巴杜还从我这买了些
But no Simon Cowell? 'Cause that would be exciting. Figure?
西蒙・考威尔没买吗？ 如果他也买了就很激动人心了，明白吗？ （此二人均为“美国偶像”节目的评委）
I'm gonna call you back a little later.
我给你回电，很快
Hey.
嘿！
Hey, Nathaniel.
嘿！纳杉尼尔
Remember me?
记得我吗？
Sorry.
抱歉
Maybe have a minute when you're done?
你拉完琴完之后有空吗？
Let me know.
完了告诉我
I just saw you, so I...
我刚才看到你，所以我…
Nothing.
没事了
Mr. Steve Lopez, Los Angeles Times, Los Angeles, California.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生，洛杉矶时报的 洛杉矶，加利福尼亚州
Hey, Nathaniel.
嘿，纳杉尼尔
I've been searching for Mr. Beethoven,
我一直在寻找贝多芬先生
but he's slipping away like a dream.
但是他就像梦境一般难以捕捉
I'm trying to get back into shape, but I don't have any sheet music.
我试着找回我的状态，但是我没有一张谱纸
Beethoven's String Quartet, Opus 59, Number 1,
贝多芬第一号弦乐四重奏，第59号作品
Violin Concerto, Opus 61 in D,
D大调小提琴协奏曲，第61号作品
Fifth Concerto, Opus 73 in E Flat, red car, green car,
降E大调第五号协奏曲，第73号作品 红车、绿车
there goes a police car, and God is right on the other side of that wall.
有辆警车开过去了 而上帝就在那面墙的另一边
I had to dig a hole to bury some human defecation.
我不得不挖个洞来埋掉一些人体排遗物
But they didn't have the human decency...
但他们连拉的时候都不注重仪表
I was looking for you.
我一直在找你
...to use the proper facilities. - I noticed that you've moved.
- 连厕所也不用 - 我注意到你搬家了
Well, it's beautiful here, because you can play music
其实，这里很漂亮，因为这里你能拉琴…
and have pigeons clapping as they take off,
鸽子也能在飞走的时候自由振翅
and right there is The Los Angeles Times Building.
而洛杉矶时报大楼就在那里
- Right, that's where I work. - Mr. Steve Lopez, staff writer.
- 对，那就是我工作的地方 - 史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生，自由撰稿人
New York, Cleveland, it doesn't matter.
纽约，克里夫兰，都没所谓
All I have to do is look up at that building
我须要做的就是抬头看这大楼…
and I know exactly where I am.
我就知道我身在何处了
I was thinking about...
我一直在想…
I'm in Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California,
我身在洛杉矶，洛杉矶，加利福尼亚
- Los Angeles Lakers. ...writing about you
- 洛杉矶湖人 - 写篇关于你的文章…
for the paper.
登在报上
Magic Johnson, Magic Johnson Theaters.
魔术师约翰逊，魔术师约翰逊戏院
Magic Johnson is a basketball player, but he's also a big, black man.
魔术师约翰逊是一个篮球运动员 但他也是一个高个子的黑人
What if I were to wanna write a story about you for the newspaper?
我为报纸写一篇关于你的报道怎样？
Los Angeles Times, Los Angeles newspaper.
洛杉矶时报，洛杉矶报纸
- Staff writer, Mr. Steve Lopez. - Yeah. Yeah, that's me.
- 自由撰稿人，史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生 - 对，对，就是我
Do you mind if I record this? And I wanna write a story about you.
介意我录音吗？因为我想写篇关于你的报道
A column about how a guy like you winds up on the street.
一个关于像你一样的街头流浪者的专栏
- What do you think of that? - Mr. Lopez needs to do
- 你觉得那怎么样？ - 洛佩兹先生需要去做…
what Mr. Lopez needs to do.
洛佩兹先生需要做的事
No one could ever stop Mr. Lopez from doing what he wants to do.
从来没有人能阻碍洛佩兹先生去做 他想要去做的事
Are you flying that plane?
你在开那架飞机吗？
No. No, I'm right here.
不，我现在站在你旁边
I don't know how God works.
我不知道上帝是怎么做的
I called Juilliard, and they said you went there, but you didn't finish.
我给朱利亚德学校打过电话 他们说你在那上过学，但没有完成学业
I bombed right out of there. I bombed out of Juilliard.
我被那里开除了，我被朱利亚德学校开除了
- Yeah, what happened? - I just... It didn't happen.
- 对，发生了什么事？ - 我只是…什么也没发生
I don't know. I don't know what happened.
我不知道，我不知道发生了什么
Anyone I could contact? Family?
有什么能联系上的熟人吗？亲人？
Family? Miss Floria Ayers, my mom.
亲人？弗洛莉亚・艾耶斯女士，我妈
She's a beautician. Beauty is art. Music is beauty.
她是个美容师，美是门艺术，音乐就是美
I don't do hair. I do my own hair,
我不会做头发，我只做自己的头发
but obviously, my mom does everybody's hair in the community.
但是很明显，我妈为社区的所有人都做头发
They would come for her. She's quite a woman.
他们都来找她，她很有女人味
But I don't know how you're gonna talk to her, though, because she passed.
但我不知道你怎样能联系上她，她过世了
Okay. Sorry to hear that.
好的，我很遗憾
Who could I call?
我能找谁？
216-962-6746.
226-962-6746
Whose number's that?
这是谁的号码？
You know, it's a dream out here, Mr. Lopez.
你知道吗，身边就是一场梦，洛佩兹先生
The sun is shining. The nights are cool and serene,
太阳高照，夜晚凉爽而静谧
and I notice that everyone is smiling.
而且我注意到所有人都在笑
- Delivered just hours before... - Americans are asking...
“- 几小时前的报道… - 美国人民在要求…”
Hi, I'm calling for Jennifer Ayers-Moore.
嗨，我想找詹妮弗・艾耶斯-摩尔
How will we finally win this war?
“我们怎么能在这场战争中最后获胜？”
Hello?
你好
Hi, this is Steve Lopez from the LA Times.
嗨，我是史蒂夫・洛佩兹，洛杉矶时报的
I spoke with your aunt, I believe, earlier. She suggested I give you a call.
早些时候我给应该是你姑姑的人打过电话 她建议我给你电话
- About what? - About your brother, Nathaniel.
- 有什么事？ - 我想谈谈你的哥哥，纳杉尼尔
Is he dead?
他死了吗？
What? No, no, no, he's alive.
什么？不，不，他还活着
Is he all right?
他还好吗？
He's... Yeah. He's homeless. I don't know if you're aware of that.
他…嗯，他现在无家可归 我不知道你对这是否有所了解
But he seems very bright, and... May I record this?
但他看起来很聪明，而且… 我能把你的话录下来吗？
And talented, obviously. Juilliard and all.
而且在朱利亚德学校里也显得很有天赋
I'm, I'm... I'm sorry.
我…我很抱歉
- Your name again, please? - Steve Lopez.
- 能再说次你的名字吗？ - 史蒂夫・洛佩兹
Mr. Lopez, why are you calling?
洛佩兹先生，你给我电话的目的是什么？
I'm gonna write a column about Nathaniel.
我要为纳杉尼尔写篇专栏报道
Why?
为什么？
Because that's what I do. Everyone has a story, and it's interesting,
因为这个是我的工作 所有人都有自己的故事，而这个故事…
you know, that a Juilliard alum is now homeless.
你知道，挺吸引人 一个来自朱利亚德艺校的人现在流落街头
But he seems smart and kind, and... And...
但他看起来很聪明也很友善，而且…
And spends his days filling the city air with violin music, and I just...
他每天不停地向这城市的空气中 注入小提琴的琴声，而我…
He plays the violin now?
他现在拉小提琴了？
He's... Yeah. Why? He used to play something else?
他…是的，为什么这么问？ 他以前用其它的乐器？
Bye, Mama.
拜，妈妈
- Good morning, Nathaniel. - Morning, Miss Little John.
- 早上好，纳杉尼尔 - 早上好，小约翰女士
So, what do you want to play for me?
那么，你要给我演奏什么
I'm going to play some Beethoven, sir. I'm crazy about Beethoven.
我会演奏几段贝多芬的曲子，先生 我非常着迷于贝多芬
He was younger than me when he started playing piano,
他在比我还年轻的时候就开始弹奏钢琴了
and I wanted to play the piano, but so many kids played it,
我也想弹奏钢琴，但是太多孩子要弹了
and there's only one at school, so it's hard to get practice time in.
而学校里只有一架钢琴，很难有练习的机会
So, I chose the cello. Hardly anyone at school wanted to play the cello.
所以我选择了大提琴 学校里几乎没有人会想拉大提琴
And Beethoven was composing when he was only 11,
而贝多芬11岁就开始作曲了
and I'm already older than that,
而我已经过了这个年纪了
so I figure I got a lot of catching up to do.
所以我想我还要下很多功夫才能迎头赶上
Let's hear you play.
让我们听你拉琴吧
He had the talent, that's for sure. I called his mother that night.
他有天分，这点是肯定的 我那天晚上就给他妈妈打了电话
I told her that I thought he was the most gifted kid I've ever met.
我告诉她，他是我见过最有天赋的孩子
I said that if he made a full commitment to music,
我说如果他能全身心地投入到音乐当中…
if he really, really gave it all he had, the whole world would open up to him.
如果他真的能够毫无保留地投入 音乐的世界将会为他打开大门
And he did. He really did.
然而他做到了，真的做到了
Go see if Martha's rollers are ready. They should be on the kitchen table.
去看看玛萨的发卷准备好了没 它们应该在厨房的桌子上
Okay, Mama.
好的，妈妈
Miss Florence, I'll be back in 10.
弗洛伦斯女士，我20分钟后回来
He ain't gonna get no sleep.
他会睡不着的
He gonna kill that little girl before he kills everybody...
他会在杀死所有人之前杀死那个小女孩…
$10,000! I told him he gotta buy me something real pretty. Real pretty.
2万美元！ 我告诉他该给我买点非常非常漂亮的东西
Before long, it got so that was all he did.
很长一段时间，他就只热衷于一件事情
No more football, no more baseball. Just music.
不再踢足球，不再玩棒球，只有音乐
Day in and day out.
一天一天过去
The whole world was changing around him.
他身边的世界一直在改变
And that was all he did.
而他只沉浸于一样东西
Music.
音乐
Hey, you awake?
嘿，还没睡？
You know what I hear when you play your music?
你知道当你拉你的琴的时候 我听到了什么吗？
I hear the voice of God coming...
我听到了上帝降临的声音…
I'm serious.
我是认真的
You got something special here, baby.
你这里有些特别的东西，宝贝
A way out.
一条出路
There is a whole world waiting for you.
音乐的世界就在那儿等着你
"Points West" by Steve Lopez.
“指向西部”，史蒂夫・洛佩兹著
Nathaniel was shy in our first encounter. Period.
纳杉尼尔在我们初次见面时有些腼腆，句号
He took a step back when I approached him to say
当我走近他时，他后退了一步
I liked the way his violin music
而我想说我喜欢听…
drowned out the jackhammers on Grand Street. Period.
他那被大街上的手提凿岩钻淹没的 小提琴琴声，句号
Nathaniel's first instrument was the cello.
纳杉尼尔的首选乐器是大提琴
Strangely, he has never had any training on the violin instrument.
奇怪的是 他从没接受过任何小提琴方面的训练
He has never had... Period.
他从没接受过…句号
He has never had any training on the violin.
他从没接受过任何小提琴方面的训练
He switched to the latter after winding up on the streets.
在他开始流落街头之后便改选了后者
One day, I asked him about his hopes and dreams.
有一天，我问他他的希望和梦想是什么
"That's easy," he said. "I'd like to get these other two strings."
“那很简单，”他说 “我希望能得到另外的两根弦”
Dear Mr. Lopez,
亲爱的洛佩兹先生
this morning I read your article about the street musician
今早我读了你那篇关于街头音乐家的文章
and was deeply moved.
我被深深地打动了
This cello is one I used for 50 years,
这把大提琴我拉了50年了
until arthritis got the better of me.
直到关节炎征服了我
Please pass it along to Mr. Ayers
请把它转交给艾耶斯先生吧
with my prayers for his health and safety.
也替我祝愿他安康
- Nathaniel! - All I'm trying to do
- 纳杉尼尔！ - 我想做的就是…
is work as hard as I can to clean up the tunnel.
尽我最大努力去把这隧道清理干净
- Hey! Nathaniel! - But they don't want me to help them.
- 纳杉尼尔！ - 但他们不愿接受我的帮助
I won't have it, you know.
我接受不了，知道吗？
- Don't want to have this degradation... - Are you out of your mind?
- 不想堕落到这种地步… - 你疯了吗？
...because they just won't respect that Beethoven...
因为他们根本不尊重贝多芬…
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
...and I try to tell every one of them, I won't have this nastiness...
而我尝试着去告诉他们 我不愿接受这污秽…
- Nathaniel! ...this degradation, I won't have it.
- 纳杉尼尔！ - 接受这种堕落，我接受不了
Don't!
别！
Don't! Don't!
不要！别去！
I'm not going to have this nastiness in this tunnel. This degradation.
我不会容忍隧道里有这种污秽，这种堕落
Good.
好极了
Remember when I said I was gonna write about you?
还记得我说我要写关于你的报道吗？
Well, I did.
呃，我写了
When people heard that you were just playing with two strings,
当人们知道你在拉只有两根弦的琴时…
some of them thought you might want something better to work with.
他们当中有人认为你会想要些更好的东西 来弹奏
No. I can't cover that.
不，我买不起这个
You don't have to pay for it. It's a gift.
你不需要付钱，有人送你的
- I'm sure it's a very beautiful instrument. - Free and clear.
- 我敢肯定这是件非常漂亮的乐器 - 免费而且干净
People are very, very generous.
人们非常非常慷慨
But, look, here's the deal.
不过，听着，有个条件
It's not safe for you to have something this valuable on the streets...
你带着这么贵重的东西 在大街上是不安全的
You don't have to worry about that, Mr. Lopez.
这点你不用担心，洛佩兹先生
I've been mugged 14 times.
我被打劫过14次了
I will fight to the death to protect this instrument.
我会用我的性命去保护这件乐器的
Right, that's my point exactly.
对，这就是我担心的
So, apparently there's a place
所以，显然，有个地方
that's a couple of blocks down that's called Lamp.
就在几个街区之外，叫做“兰普”
- I can't go... No, I can't go there. - And I... Hold on.
- 我不能去…不，我不能去那儿 - 而我…打住
I can't go... No, I can't go there.
我不能去…不，我不能去那儿
- They smoke cigarettes. - I talked to the guy.
- 他们在那吸烟… - 我和那的人说过了
- He says you can keep it there. - They drop the butts on the ground.
- 他说你能把琴放在那里 - 他们把烟屁股直接扔到地上
They do it to torment me. They just... They do it to torment me.
他们这么做就是为了折磨我，他们… 他们这么做就是为了折磨我
That's the deal. You wanna play this, you gotta do it there.
这是条件，你想拉这把琴，你就得去那里拉
- I can't do that. - Oh, yeah.
- 我做不到 - 噢，是吗
Except for this one time. Take it out and give it a test drive or whatever.
除了这次，你可以拿它出来试拉一下之类的
- So I can play it here? - For a couple minutes,
- 那我能在这拉琴了？ - 就几分钟
and then we're gonna bring it to Lamp.
之后我们就要把它带到兰普去
Laying in there like a pig in a blanket.
就像躺在毯子中的猪崽一样
Only... Only the greats. Really, only the greats.
只有那些伟人，真的，只有那些伟人
Yo-Yo Ma, Jacqueline du Pr¨¦,
马友友，杰奎琳・杜・普蕾
and the coolest cucumber of them all is
而他们当中最美味的一位就是
Janos Starker.
詹诺斯・斯塔克 （此三人均为大提琴演奏家）
Gotta put rosin on your bow. It's just like feeding a parakeet.
一定要给琴弓上松香 要像喂小鹦鹉一样仔细
A bow needs rosin just like a police car needs prisoners.
琴弓需要抹松香，就像警车需要填囚犯
So pack it up. We'll bring it to Lamp, you can get back at it.
那就装好吧，我们要把它带到兰普去 你可以回去找它
I haven't really gotten a chance to know her yet.
我还没有机会认识她呢
- So... - I'm not saying you can't play.
- 那么… - 我没说过你不能弹奏它
- You can. Just not here. - This is the perfect music environment
- 你可以，只是不能在这里 - 这里就是演奏音乐的…
- for playing music. - This?
- 完美环境 - 这里？
- No. - Yes.
- 不 - 是的
This is a sidewalk, okay?
这里只是条人行道，好吧？
- That's the deal. We made a deal. - No, no, no. You'll break the bridge.
- 这就是条件，我们说好了的 - 不，不，你会弄坏弦桥的
- You'll put water in it, you'll drown her. - That's what I'll do?
- 你会把水弄进去，你会把她淹死的 - 我会做这些事？
- It will be ruined. - Why would I damage it?
- 它会被毁掉的 - 我怎么会去损坏它
- I gave you the damn thing. - It won't play right ever,
- 这鬼东西是我带给你的啊 - 它再也对不上调了
- because, Mr. Lopez, you'll ruin it. - I'm not going to...
- 因为，洛佩兹先生，你会毁了它 - 我不会…
I'm not gonna see you get killed over this.
我不会看着这东西让你送命的
You don't know what you're doing. Let me put it away myself.
你根本不知道你在做什么 让我自己把它收好
Then put it away.
那就收好它
Thank you.
谢谢
Because when you start a relationship with somebody...
因为当你和某个人刚开始一段感情…
- Don't make a big deal of it, okay? - It is a big deal.
- 别太当一回事好吗？ - 这是件大事
In a minute, you'll have it set up down at Lamp
很快，你会在兰普把它架好…
and be playing like you never stopped.
然后就可以不停地弹奏了
- Right? - It's brand-new, this relationship.
- 好吧？ - 这是一段全新的感情
- I don't want this relationship to end. - Do you know where it is?
- 我不想让这段感情终结 - 你知道那地方在哪儿吗？
- No, I can't do that. - Just leave that there. I'll drive you.
- 不，我做不到 - 把它放下就好，我会开车送你去
I have my cart there. I could get it in my cart.
我还有手推车，我可以把它放到里面去
What are you doing? You're gonna let go.
你在干什么？你放手好吧
- Just let your fingers go. - Does anyone...
- 把你手指松开就好 - 有人…
Does anyone see what he's doing right here?
有人看到他在干什么吗？
- He's stealing it. - I'II... I'll meet you there.
- 他在偷东西 - 我…我们在那里碰头吧
San Julian and 6th.
圣朱利安和第六大街
All right?
好吧？
- I'll drive. You walk. - I know where it is...
- 我开车，你走路 - 我知道在哪儿
See you in a half hour?
半小时后见？
For cash money I got speed, man.
给现金的话很快到手，老兄
I'm good.
不用了
Jesus.
上帝啊
Tennis shoes.
网球鞋
Oh, boy.
（兰普社区） 噢，老天
One at a time. One at a time.
一个一个来，一个一个来
The pusher. Ten cents.
推销员，卖10分
- Say, hey, is David here? - Yes?
- 喂，嘿，大卫在吗？ - 什么事？
I'm here for David.
我来找大卫的
- Who? - David.
- 谁？ - 大卫
David? I can go get him.
大卫？我叫他来
Thanks.
谢谢
David!
大卫！
Hey.
嘿
- Hi. - Hi. You a volunteer?
- 嗨 - 嗨，你是来做义工的？
Steve Lopez, Los Angeles Times.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹，洛杉矶时报的
- Don't be scared. Come in. - Thanks.
- 别害怕，请进 - 谢谢
Every staff has a key,
所有的员工都有钥匙
so if he does come by and I'm not here, then anybody can get it for him.
所以如果他到了而我不在 其他人会给他开门的
- Well, he'll be here. - Okay.
- 呃，他会来的 - 好的
He said he was coming.
他说过他会来
Can you sign in for me?
你能帮我登记吗？
- Sure. - Thanks.
- 当然 - 谢谢
- Afternoon. - Hi. How are you?
- 下午好 - 嗨，你好吗？
I mean, it's tired. It's like they can't find the medication
我说的是，他们累了 就好象他们没有办法帮我找到…
that's right for me, you know?
合适的药物，知道吗？
- You know what I'm trying to say? - Yeah.
- 知道我想说的意思吗？ - 是的
When they put me on lithium,
当他们给我吃锂片…
it was like a portion of my brain
我的部分大脑就好像…
was fully functional.
能够正常工作了
You know what I mean?
知道我的意思吗？
Because it's like when I take the lithium and everything,
因为就好像当我吃下锂片和其他药时…
it totally eliminates the voices in my mind
我头脑里的声音全都消失了
when they first start rising up,
就在那些声音响起的时候…
you know, and it stops them, right there.
知道吗？那些药物就立刻让它们消失了
I don't like that, because they just stop them.
我不喜欢这样，因为它们把那些声音弄没了
Because, see, sometimes those voices comfort me.
因为，看，有时候那些声音能让我安心
And when they comfort me, if they give me all this lithium,
而当它们安抚我的时候 如果他们给我吃那些锂片
then I no longer have the voices to comfort me.
我就不能听到那些安抚我的声音了
You understand what I'm saying?
我明白我说的吗？
Do you feel what I'm saying to you?
你能感受到我说的话吗？
- You mind if I sit here? - Not at all.
- 介意我坐下吗？ - 一点也不
All right.
好的
- I'm Steve. - I'm Steve, too.
- 我叫史蒂夫 - 我也叫史蒂夫
Oh, boy. Hi.
噢，天啊，嗨
- I knew I picked the right spot. - Yeah, you're good.
- 我就知道我坐对地方了 - 是的，你很会选
So are you a new Lamp staff, or...
那么你是兰普的新员工，或者…
- No. I'm just waiting for somebody. - Okay.
- 不，我只是在等人 - 好的
I just try to keep Leeann happy.
我只是想让莉安高兴
He is a bright spot in my life. We value the same things.
他是我生命中的亮点，我们有共同的价值观
And we're comfortable together.
我们在一起的时候很自在
Thank you, Leeann. That's so nice to hear you say that.
谢谢你，莉安，听到你这么说我很高兴
I call him Piggy Boy and stuff like that,
我用“小猪”之类的名字叫他
but I shouldn't, because he's in a bad shape.
但我不该这么做，因为他最近状况很糟
We thought his problem was cocaine.
我们认为他的问题是可卡因
- But it was pancreatic cancer. - Yeah?
- 但我认为是胰腺癌 - 是吗？
KK's French, Egyptian, and African-American,
KK有法国、埃及和非裔美国人血统
and I am a quarter French.
而我有四分之一法国血统
I know about disease. I know how to treat it.
我了解疾病，我知道怎么治疗它们
Now I understand people. I can help so many people fast,
现在我能理解他人 我能很快地帮助很多人
and I can comfort them.
并且让他们安心
They've got Italian nurses, 6'4", in the county hospital.
在郡立医院有几个意大利人护士，6尺4寸高
And one of them talked to me like I was trash.
其中一人和我说话的态度就好像我是垃圾
Now, this is probably that the hour of power that the Bible speaks of,
现在 这或许就是圣经里头说的神威显现的时刻
somebody who speaks a harsh language, will have what the computer...
当有人说难听的话时，就会让电脑的…
The computer is probably the beast.
电脑或许就是那猛兽
My aunt ended up with 16 shock treatments
我姑姑因为26次休克疗法死了
because she didn't want to go to bed
因为她不想和她那…
with her sex-crazed husband.
有疯狂性欲的丈夫上床
He was paying call girls $100 apiece,
他会为每个应召女郎支付200美元
going to bed with them and coming home
和她们上床之后回家
and giving my aunt all kinds of diseases.
然后把所有的疾病都传染给了我姑姑
I got sick. I was working over there.
我生病了，我曾在那里干过活
And I got sicker than a dog one day. I got an infection in my esophagus.
然后有天我病得像条狗，我的食道被感染了
The neighbor's dog was sick one day and the only thing I had on hand
有天邻居家的狗生病了，而我手头只有…
was a packet of tetracycline for my chickens.
一包给我的鸡吃的四环素
So they wouldn't... They were too busy to treat her at the moment.
所以他们不能…他们太忙了 不能在当时就给她治疗
- You're fantastic. - They'd already given her...
- 你太神奇了 - 他们已经给了她…
Ice cold. Ice cold.
冷冰冰，冷冰冰
"Points West" by Steve Lopez.
“指向西部”，史蒂夫・洛佩兹著
I put Nathaniel's new instruments in safekeeping and waited.
我把纳杉尼尔的新乐器放妥后就等着他
Fifteen minutes. Thirty minutes. An hour.
15分钟，30分钟，一个小时
Too long, in fact, 'cause guess what, schmuck,
实际上，太久了 知道吗，你个笨蛋
you got a deadline tomorrow.
明天就是交稿期限了
And the story of a guy not showing up
而故事的主人公却还没有出现
is not a story.
那就写不成报道了
Nathaniel. Nathaniel. Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔，纳杉尼尔，纳杉尼尔啊
Okay.
好了
So, you guys are basically united by non-belief.
那你们基本上是因为反对信仰而联合起来了
- That's right. - Yeah.
- 是的 - 好的
So, do you non-gather?
那么，你们反对集会？
And non-worship?
也反对礼拜？
We tried, but...
我们尝试过，但是…
- Not a lot to talk about. - Yeah.
- 不能透露太多是吧 - 是的
- Now we have a website. - Swell.
- 现在我们建了一个网站了 - 不错
Anything else you don't believe in?
你们还有其他不信的事情吗？
- Sorry. - Yeah, actually...
- 抱歉 - 是的，实际上…
- Sorry. - Okay.
- 抱歉 - 好的
- Lopez. - Can you hear this?
- 我是洛佩兹 - 听得到这个吗？
Sorry, can't hear you.
抱歉，没听到
I said, can you hear this?
我说，能听到这个吗？
This family thinks it can have this conversation at every step.
这家人以为每一步都能像这样地交谈
This is my apartment. This is my apartment.
这是我的宿舍，这是我的宿舍
This is my apartment.
这是我的宿舍
Nathaniel Anthony Ayers Junior. N-A-T-H-A...
纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世 N-A-T-H-A…
- I need Charles for the practice. ...because you're so good.
- 我要和查尔斯一起练习 - …因为你弹得很好了
I am so good, but I still have to tweak things so I can win.
我是很棒，但为了获胜我一样需要全力以赴
There's a fine line in performances.
表演的顺序排得很不错
- I mean, I can't let her beat me. - I really have to practice.
- 我是说，我不能让她打败我 - 我真的还需要练习
Half an hour is all it takes for me.
只要给我半个小时就好
Half an hour.
半个小时
Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔
- Nathaniel. - Nathaniel.
- 纳杉尼尔 - 纳杉尼尔
- Nathaniel. - Nathaniel?
- 纳杉尼尔 - 纳杉尼尔？
- Nathaniel Ayers. - Nathaniel.
- 纳杉尼尔・艾耶斯 - 纳杉尼尔
- Nathaniel. Nathaniel. - Nathaniel.
- 纳杉尼尔，纳杉尼尔 - 纳杉尼尔
- Ayers! - Nathaniel!
- 艾耶斯！ - 纳杉尼尔！
Ma, I'm good, honestly, it's just that...
妈，我没事，真的，只是…
- I'm real proud of you, baby. - Thank you.
- 我真的为你感到自豪，宝贝 - 谢谢
It's just that I'm not always so sure I know what's going on, and...
只是我并不总是能确定正在发生的事 而且…
You are gonna be fine.
你会好起来的
It's so frightening, and...
太吓人了，而且…
And I'm having trouble differentiating certain things.
而且我不能区分某些东西
Keeping things separated.
把事情分清
If you'd like to make a call, please hang up and try again.
如果你还要打电话，请挂机后再尝试
If you need help...
如果你需要帮助…
- That's where your pain is stored. - Nathaniel.
- 这就是忍受痛苦的地方 - 纳杉尼尔
- Nathaniel. Nathaniel. - Paint your chest white.
- 纳杉尼尔，纳杉尼尔 - 把你的胸口漆白
Protect her from the pain.
保护她免受痛苦
Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔
I'll be here to protect you from the pain.
我会在这保护你免受痛苦
- I'll protect you from the pain. - I'll protect you from the pain.
- 我会保护你免受痛苦 - 我会保护你免受痛苦
I'll protect you from the pain.
我会保护你免受痛苦
I'll protect you from their eyes and ears.
我会保护你不被他们看到和听到
Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔
Are you finding this piece to be beyond your abilities?
你觉得这曲子超出你的能力了吗？
They're listening to you, Nathaniel.
他们在听着你，纳杉尼尔
They can hear your thoughts, Nathaniel.
他们能听到你的心思，纳杉尼尔
- I can hear your thoughts, Nathaniel. - Well, then I suggest you do better.
- 我能听到你的心思，纳杉尼尔 - 那么，我建议做的更好些
- Don't think, Nathaniel. - Bar 179, ladies and gentlemen.
- 别想，纳杉尼尔 - 第279小节，女士们先生们
- Run away, Nathaniel. - Run away, Nathaniel.
- 快跑，纳杉尼尔 - 快跑，纳杉尼尔
Run away, Nathaniel.
快跑，纳杉尼尔
- Come on. Run. - You should run.
- 加油，跑 - 你应该跑
- You'll have to hide, Nathaniel. - Run!
- 你必须要躲起来，纳杉尼尔 - 跑！
- You'll never get out of there. - You'll never get out of there.
- 你永远都逃不出去 - 你永远都逃不出去
- Run! Run! Run! - You'll never get out.
- 跑！跑！跑！ - 你永远都逃不了
- Quick, like a jackrabbit. - Nathaniel.
- 快，就像野兔一样 - 纳杉尼尔
They're white, heartless, aren't they?
他们很白，却没有心，不是吗？
- Heartless. - Hide.
- 没有心 - 躲
Hide for me here, Nathaniel.
为了我躲起来，纳杉尼尔
We see you, Nathaniel.
我们看到你了，纳杉尼尔
- They'll see you, Nathaniel. - Whiteness.
- 他们也会看到你，纳杉尼尔 - 白
- There's no hiding, Nathaniel. - Whiteness.
- 躲不开，纳杉尼尔 - 白
You'll never hide well enough.
你永远都藏不好
...turn you white... - Whiteness!
- …把你变白… - 白！
- No hiding for you, Nathaniel. - Whiteness. Whiteness.
- 你躲不了，纳杉尼尔 - 白，白
Whiteness.
白
You'll take it, because I want my out.
你必须接受，因为我这就要出去
Detroit? Anger management.
底特律？愤怒管理疗法
It's amazing, right?
令人惊叹，是吗？
Does it look like I need some anger management to you?
你看我需要接受愤怒管理治疗吗？
Yeah. Man, I'll take him any day.
是啊，老兄，我每天都会带他来的
He quiets everybody down.
他让大家伙都安静下来了
- What does he have, schizophrenia? - I don't know.
- 他这是什么病？精神分裂？ - 我不清楚
Well, we should hook him up with psychiatric services and find out, right?
那我们该帮他联系一些精神诊断服务 好找到答案，是吗？
Yeah, I don't get too hung up on diagnosis.
我不太支持让他去做诊断
What do you mean?
什么意思？
But how do you help somebody if you don't know what they have?
那不知道一个人的病情，要怎么去治好他？
Look at these people.
看看这些人
Every one of them's been diagnosed more than you can imagine.
他们当中的每个人都接受过 多到你想象不了的诊断
And as far as I can tell, it hasn't done them any good.
而迄今为止，我能告诉你 那样做没有给他们带来任何好处
But he needs medication, right?
但他需要药物治疗，不是吗？
I'll tell you one thing he doesn't need.
我来告诉你他唯一不需要的东西：
One more person telling him he needs medication.
再有人告诉他他需要药物治疗
Son of a bitch.
这混蛋
- Where'd he go? - Who?
- 他又跑哪儿了 - 谁？
- Nathaniel. - Don't ask me, dude.
- 纳杉尼尔 - 别问我，老兄
- Thanks, Steve. - You're welcome, Steve.
- 多谢，史蒂夫 - 不客气，史蒂夫
- Keep walking. Keep walking! - There's a cop over there.
- 快走，快走 - 那有个警察
- He'll shoot a nigga with a pop. - You got that cheese, huh?
- 他会用枪打一个黑鬼 - 耗子找到奶酪了吗？
- You're right about that cheese. - Hold on, hold on. Hold up.
- 奶酪这事你说对了 - 打住，打住
Hey, wait!
嘿，等等！
Want to buy some candy?
想来些糖果吗？
Five-o. Five-o.
5-0，5-0
No way this is gonna be...
不可能会这样…
That boy's not the real police.
这小子不是真警察
Oh, man. Hell, man. Where's my piece at, nigga?
噢，老兄 去死，老兄，我那份在哪儿，黑鬼？
Back up.
后退
I went over to the library.
我去了趟图书馆
I thought I might pick up some sheet music.
我以为我能在那捡到些谱纸
Sonata Number 1, F Major, Opus 5,
F大调第一奏鸣曲，第五号作品
Sonata Number 2 in A Major, Opus 69 for String Quartet.
A大调第二奏鸣曲，第69号作品的弦乐重奏
What happened? Somebody get beat up?
怎么了？有人被揍了？
Overdose, I think.
吸毒过量，我想
The other night, someone... There was a beating over here.
有一天夜里，有人… 这里有场打斗
Someone got bones rearranged in their face. It was just crazy.
有人的脸被打碎了，这真疯狂
I don't understand why anybody would do something like that.
我不明白为什么有人会做这样的事
- This where you sleep? - I used to sleep on Wall Street,
- 这就是你睡觉的地方？ - 我曾在华尔街睡过
but it's too dirty.
不过那里太脏了
You know, Mr. Lopez, my vision...
知道吗，洛佩兹先生，我的憧憬…
I hate to admit it, but I'm gonna have to be like Beethoven.
我讨厌承认这点 但是我想成为和贝多芬一样的人
Just do what he did and just die. Thank you, Mr. Lopez.
做他做过的事然后死去 谢谢你，洛佩兹先生
My vision is not far-off stuff,
我的憧憬并不是遥不可及的东西
just basically getting across the street safely.
就仅仅是安全地横过马路
Honor thy father and mother, and then, hopefully,
带给我父母荣誉，然后，希望…
the music will take care of itself.
我的音乐就自生自灭吧
That's really all you can do.
这的确就是我能做的
I mean, when you think about it,
意思是，你怎么认为？
there's not much that you can do other than that.
除此之外我也做不了其他的事情
- Would you care for a drink? - I'm fine.
- 来点喝的吗？ - 不必了
Thanks.
谢谢
Gotta tuck this guy in here, nice and safe.
要把这家伙塞到这里，塞好塞安全
Put that down there. Make sure this corner...
把这放到这，确保这角落…
You can rest on this.
你可以睡在这上面
Do you think of writers often, Mr. Lopez?
你对作家常有，洛佩兹先生…
Do you think of writers the way I think about musicians?
你对作家常有像我对音乐家一样的想法吗？
I write for a living,
我以写作谋生
and it's not like it used to be.
而现在写作和以前不一样了
I love thinking about musicians.
我喜欢想着音乐家
I imagine Beethoven and Mozart in that window where the light is,
想象贝多芬和莫扎特就在那亮灯的窗户里
and they just hunger and they thirst like we do.
他们就像我们一样渴着饿着
It's angelic.
这想法就像天使一样
I believe these children of God are gonna be okay tonight.
我相信这些神的子民们今晚会安然无恙的
They're gonna sleep and dream as humans do.
他们会像人类一样睡去和做梦
Our Father,
我们…
who art in Heaven,
在天上的父
hallowed be thy name.
愿人都尊你的名为圣
Thy kingdom come,
愿你的国降临
thy will be done,
愿你的旨意行在地上
on earth as it is in heaven.
如同行在天上
Give us this day our daily bread...
我们日用的饮食，今日赐给我们
Just keep it coming. There's plenty.
“继续来吧，还有很多”
And forgive us our trespasses,
免我们的过犯
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
如同我们免了人的过犯
I knew only part of his story.
我只知道他人生的一部分
I knew him playing the violin on a dairy crate in the morning sun,
我知道他在晨光中 坐在牛奶箱上拉小提琴
suspended somewhere between boy genius and lost traveler.
游离在音乐神童和迷失旅人之间
Every night, my friend Nathaniel tucks his instruments away
每天晚上 我的朋友纳杉尼尔都把他的乐器塞好
and lays his head among the predators and hustlers,
在一群掠食者、皮条客…
among fallen drunks sprawled in the streets,
和在街头四仰八叉的倒地醉汉之间…
as rats the size of meatloaves dart out of the drains to feed off the squalor.
在如同烘肉卷大小的老鼠窜出水渠 到垃圾堆中觅食之时，倒头睡去
... lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
不叫我们遇见试探，救我们脱离凶恶
For thine is the kingdom,
因为国度、权柄…
the power and the glory,
和荣耀，全是你的
forever.
直到永远
Forever and ever.
从过往直到永远
I tell him this is no place for him. He says he wants to be here.
我告诉他这不是他呆的地方 他说他想留在这里
He says this is his choice.
他说这是他的选择
Should I take him at his word, or should I try to force him inside?
我该听从他的话，还是强迫他住进去？
Wouldn't a little arm-twisting be more humane
使用一点暴力不会比把他留在…
than leaving him here on the streets
这满是破碎无助灵魂的国度…
in this lost colony of broken, helpless souls?
的大街上更仁慈些吗？
I hope you sleep well, Mr. Lopez.
我希望你能睡好，洛佩兹先生
I hope the whole world sleeps well.
我希望全世界都能睡好
A-D-A-M C-R-A-N-E. He wants to meet you.
（指向西部：老鼠和大提琴的暮光协奏曲） A-D-A-M C-R-A-N-E，他想见你
Who? The guy from the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Adam Crane.
谁？ 一个来自洛杉矶爱乐乐团的，亚当・克莱恩
Wondering if you wanna come hear a concert
他想知道你是否愿意约个时间…
at Disney Hall some time as his guest.
作为他的嘉宾到迪斯尼音乐厅听场音乐会
They're doing Beethoven.
他们要演奏贝多芬的作品
- Ludwig van? - Beethoven, all season long.
- 路德维奇・范・贝多芬？ - 贝多芬，整个季度
They got one coming up. The Third.
他们接下来有一场，三号
- Well, what's the date today? - No, the Third Symphony.
- 那么，今天是几号？ - 不，第三号交响乐
I'll cause a scene. I don't wanna cause a scene.
我会出丑的，我不想出丑
I don't wanna stick out or anything like that.
我不想类似这样的事情发生
So it's just... It's impossible. It can't happen.
所以这…不可能的，不会发生的
What if I could get us in for a rehearsal?
如果能安排我们听他们排练呢？
Nathaniel, let's go.
纳杉尼亚，走吧
What I did with the keys right here...
我这些钥匙要怎么办…
Come on. Lock up the cart.
来吧，把手推车锁起来
- No. You know what, Mr. Lopez? - Come on, we gotta go.
- 不，知道吗，洛佩兹先生？ - 来吧，我们要出发了
I can't leave my stuff here with these rascals.
我不能把我的东西和这些无赖留在一起
They can't be trusted. They'll do anything.
他们不可信，他们什么都能干
Oh, no. We have an entire orchestra waiting for us. We are gonna go.
噢，不，有一整支管弦乐队在等着我们 我们得马上走
They have drug addicts and cigarette smokers here,
这有瘾君子和烟鬼
and they will steal all of what I have.
他们会把我的东西偷光
- No one is going to steal your shit. - I can't leave it.
- 没人会偷你这些破玩意儿 - 我不能扔下它
No, no. We have to get in touch with the mayor...
不，不，我们要联系…
- Nathaniel, it's garbage. ...Antonio Villaraigosa...
- 纳杉尼尔，这些都是垃圾 - …安东尼奥・维拉雷格萨市长…
...or the president. - No one is gonna steal this garbage.
- …或者总统 - 没人要偷这些垃圾
- In the corner... - No, no, no, Mr. Lopez,
- 推到角落 - 不，不，洛佩兹先生
I'm not gonna be able to make it up there.
我想我去不了那里了
Okay. Oh, boy.
好，噢，天
Fantasia. Walt Disney Hall. Donald Duck.
幻想曲，华特・迪斯尼音乐厅，唐老鸭
I have to deal with things here
我必须把这边的事处理好
because I wouldn't leave a dog with these people here.
因为我不能把宠物狗和这些人留在一起
Right. Okay. Fine.
好，好，好
A cockroach does not tell a greyhound what to do.
一只蟑螂不会告诉一只灰狗要干什么
It's fine! Do you understand? It's fine.
好！明白吗？没问题
I do not give a smooth fart if we go or not. Do you understand?
我屁也不关心我们能不能去，明白吗？
There are a million other things I could be doing right now.
我现在有上万件事情可以去做
Obligations, things that people pay me to do.
我的职务，人们付钱让我做的事
I have a job. I'm a professional person.
我有工作，我是专业人士
- Sorry. - All right.
- 抱歉 - 没关系
What?
什么？
Still not gonna leave my cart here.
还是不能把我的手推车留在这
Okay.
好
Pick a side.
选边吧
The company is offering you a very generous exit package.
公司正向你提供一份优厚的离职补贴
Yeah.
是的
- I understand how difficult this is. - Wait!
- 我明白这决定有多难 - 等等！
Right.
是啊
Unfortunately, this is the reality of our business.
很不幸，这就是我们之间这买卖的现实
Nathaniel, hard left coming up right here.
纳杉尼尔，就那个急左转弯
Mr. Lopez, are you okay?
洛佩兹先生，你还好吧？
How long has it been since you've been in a concert hall?
你有多久没进过音乐厅了？
This is great.
这真棒
There's the conductor.
那是指挥
- Just us. - Yeah, just us.
- 只有我们 - 是啊，只有我们
It's the way it should be.
就应该这样
- He's in the room. - Who is?
- 他就在这大厅里 - 谁？
Beethoven.
贝多芬
Sing the hate out!
把怨气唱出来！
Stop.
别这么说
- All right. - Strong finish!
- 好了 - 热吻结束
Get up there.
快上台吧
I'm telling you, it was such an unbelievable experience,
我告诉你，这是一次难以置信的体验
the whole thing, the whole day.
整件事，一整天
And if you had seen him, if you could have felt him...
如果你能见到他，如果你能感受他
I mean, it's the same hall.
我说，就在同一间大厅里
We're listening to the same goddamn music, but... But no.
我们在听同一段该死的音乐，但，但不是
You see him, it's one thing, but you feel him...
见到他本人，是一回事，但感受他…
I'm watching him. He's watching the music.
我欣赏着他，他欣赏着音乐
And while they're playing, I say,
当他们在演奏的时候，我说：
"My God, there is something higher out there.
“老天，那有些高高在上的东西”
"Something higher out there, and he lives in it, and he's with it."
“高高在上的东西，而他活在其中 他们共存着”
I've never even experienced it, but I can tell...
我从没有过这样的体验，但我说的出
I don't even know what you fucking call it.
我甚至不知道该他妈怎么叫它
- Grace. - What? What is it?
- 高雅 - 什么？说什么？
- Grace. - All right. That's grace?
- 高雅 - 好吧，那很高雅吗？
- Yeah. - Thank you. Yeah.
- 是的 - 谢谢你，没错
To be there with him like that
像这样和他一起
and see the way that he is transported. He surrenders.
看到他心醉神迷的样子 他屈服了
Damn it, honey.
该死，亲爱的
I mean, I've never loved anything the way that he loves music.
我从没像他热爱音乐那样地热爱过什么东西
Hey, come on. I'm thinking about my day.
嘿，别这样 我想的是那天的事
I'm thinking about my day. I wasn't thinking about you.
我想的是那天的事，不是在想你
That I believe, honey.
我相信这点，亲爱的
Call the mayor. He's been trying to reach you.
给市长电话 他一直在找你
- Which mayor? - The mayor!
- 哪个市长？ - 那个市长！
Okay.
好
Call the mayor.
给市长电话
Thank you.
谢谢
"Points West" by Frank Sinatra.
“指向西部”，弗兰克・希纳特拉著
Every now and then, in this city of innumerable wrongs,
有时，在这错漏百出的城市…
the powers that be get things right.
总有恰当的力量把事情扶正
Los Angeles has the ignominious distinction
洛杉矶有着不光彩的名声
of being the homeless capital of the nation,
因为这里有着全国最多的流浪者
and skid row is ground zero of the crisis.
然而贫民窟中却毫无危象
So, I am pleased to announce
所以，我很高兴宣布…
that I am increasing the city's financial commitment to this area
我将会对这一地区的市政资金投入…
by $50 million.
增加五千万美元
Every now and then,
有时…
the words I write do not leap straight from this page to the ether.
我所写下的词句并不会化为虚无
Instead, every now and then,
相反，有时…
they reach the right reader at the right time.
（市长承诺拨款五千万帮助贫民窟的流浪者） 它们会在恰当的时机，到达恰当的读者手中
Every now and then, the hearts, minds and wallets
有时，市政官员的心灵、思维…
of the city's officials open simultaneously.
和钱包都会在同一时间敞开
And when that happens, every now and then,
而当这样的事情发生时，有时…
the city is a better place for it.
能让这城市变得更美好
- Steve. - Yeah?
- 史蒂夫 - 什么事？
Your boyfriend is downstairs.
你男朋友在楼下
Thank you.
谢谢
That's funny.
这么说很有趣
- Nathaniel? You all right? - I'm good.
- 纳杉尼尔？你没事吧？ - 我很好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是的
You need something?
你需要什么吗？
A man only needs what he can carry, Mr. Lopez,
一个人只需要他能承受的东西，洛佩兹先生
and I have all I can carry right here. I have my bedding.
而我已经拥有了我能承受的东西 我有我的床褥
- I have my drums. I have my flower. - Yeah. Okay.
- 我的鼓，我的花 - 是啊，好的
- I have my water bottle. I have it all. - Hey, listen, listen. Listen.
- 还有我的水瓶，我全都有了 - 嘿，听着，听着
You can't hang out here.
你不能在这打发时间
- I can't? - You can't hang out here.
- 不能吗？ - 你不能在这里打发时间
You can't. Sorry.
不能，抱歉
I don't mind that at all, Mr. Lopez. Not at all.
我一点也不介意，洛佩兹先生 一点也不
You understand, right? It's a... It's a thing. Policy.
你能理解的，对吧？ 就是…就是那玩意儿，规定
- I'll be over here if you need me. - Over there?
- 如果需要我的话我就在这里 - 在那里？
Okay. You all right?
好的，你还好吧？
Yeah, I just... You know, I... Yeah.
嗯，我只是…你知道我…嗯
Sorry. I gotta...
抱歉，我有事…
All right, Mr. Lopez, I completely understand that you're working.
没关系，洛佩兹先生 我完全明白你在工作
You're working. You have to work. People have to work.
你在工作，你得工作，人们都得工作
All right, get out of the way when people are working,
好吧，他们在工作的时候别碍着他们
because you don't wanna stand out there
因为你不想在人们工作时…
in front of people, especially not Mr. Lopez.
妨碍他们，特别是洛佩兹先生
You stand in front of Mr. Lopez, he's gonna tell you to get out of here.
你碍着洛佩兹先生了，他要叫你走开
So, it's a lot of work.
所以，一大堆工作
- I think he's good. You know, I really do. - I'm sure...
- 我觉得他很棒，知道吗，我的确这么想 - 我确信…
I mean, I just... This is great. I think... I think it'll really help.
我的意思是，我只是…这样很不错 我觉得…觉得这样有帮助
I feel like you are exactly what he needs.
我觉得你才是他确切需要的人
Well, thank you.
很感谢你这么说
- Does that make sense? - Yes, it does.
- 这样说得通吗？ - 是的，的确
- Graham Claydon. Thank you. - At your service.
（洛杉矶爱乐乐团主大提琴手） - 格拉汉・克莱顿，谢谢你 - 乐意为您效劳
All we need is a place for them to meet and rehearse, like an apartment.
我们需要的就是一个会面和练习的地方 类似一间宿舍
You're asking for an apartment for Nathaniel?
你在为纳杉尼尔申请一间宿舍？
- Yeah. - Does he want an apartment? Thanks.
- 是的 - 他想住宿舍吗？谢谢
- Yes. - And he told you this?
- 是的 - 他本人告诉你的？
- Yes. - You're so full of shit, Lopez.
- 是的 - 你满嘴的屁话，洛佩兹
- I don't want an apartment. - Good, 'cause it's not.
- 我不想住宿舍 - 对，因为那不是宿舍
It's actually a music studio
那实际上是间音乐工作室
for Mr. Claydon to give you the cello lessons.
专为克莱顿先生给你上大提琴课的
Well, why don't we have Mr. Claydon come down here?
那为什么不让克莱顿先生到这里来呢？
This is a perfect place to play in, the tunnel.
这里是拉琴的绝佳地点，隧道
No, Mr. Claydon doesn't like tunnels.
不，克莱顿先生不喜欢隧道
We'll just have Mr. Claydon come here to do the lesson.
我们只需要让克莱顿先生到这里来上课
- He says it has to be quiet. - Well...
- 他说必须找个安静的地方 - 那…
It has to be quiet for the cello lessons, so your apartment...
他说必须找个安静的地方上大提琴课 所以你的宿舍…
It's not my apartment.
那不是我的宿舍
I know. I know. The apartment that belongs to no one.
我知道，我知道，那宿舍没人住
I don't have an apartment. I don't wanna be in an apartment.
我没有宿舍，我不想住宿舍
I don't need an apartment.
我不需要宿舍
Beethoven lives out in the freshness of the air.
贝多芬住在新鲜的空气里
Nathaniel, the apartment is not the point.
纳杉尼尔，宿舍不是重点
He's the leader of Los Angeles.
贝多芬是洛杉矶的领袖
- It's an opportunity. - "Angeles" means "angels." You can't...
- 这是个绝佳的机会 - “杉矶”是“天使”的意思，你不能…
- You can't hold down angels. - Do you want the opportunity?
- 你不能抑制天使升空 - 你想抓住这个机会吗？
- You can't clip angels. - Stop.
- 你不能束缚天使 - 住口
- Do you want an opportunity or not? - Do you have an apartment?
- 你到底想不想要这个机会？ - 你住过宿舍吗？
No. I have a house.
不，我有栋房子
So angry. Yelling.
真生气，嗓门都高了
It doesn't make sense.
这不合理啊
- Do you have a family? - What?
- 你有家人吗？ - 什么？
Are you a married man?
你结婚了吗？
- Is there a Mrs. Steve Lopez? - No.
- 有位史蒂夫・洛佩兹太太吗？ - 没
I did. Mary. But we split up.
我结过婚，她叫玛丽，但我们分开了
We have a son, Thomas. He's in college now.
我们有个儿子，托马斯 他现在上大学了
Mr. Steve Lopez, Mr. Thomas Steve Lopez, Mrs. Mary Steve Lopez.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生 托马斯・史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生 玛丽・史蒂夫・洛佩兹太太
Not Mrs. Lopez. Mary Weston.
不是洛佩兹太太，她叫玛丽・韦斯顿
- Mrs. Mary Weston Steve Lopez. - No. Just Mary Weston. Period.
- 玛丽・韦斯顿・史蒂夫・洛佩兹太太 - 不是，就玛丽・韦斯顿，句号
We were married. We're not anymore, so now she's just Mary.
我们做过夫妻，现在不是了 所以她就叫玛丽
You were married to Mary, but you're not married to Mary anymore.
你和玛丽结过婚，但你们不再是夫妻了
Correct. Don't ask me how.
没错，别问我原因
Mrs. Floria Ayers, Miss Jennifer Ayers.
弗洛莉亚・艾耶斯太太 詹妮弗・艾耶斯女士
And then there was Mr. Nathaniel Anthony Ayers Sr.
还有个老纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯先生
He was a big man. He had big hands.
他是个大块头，他有双大手
I have very small hands.
我只有双小手
Fit around a violin, a cello.
适合拉小提琴、大提琴
Mr. Ayers was a big man, but he wasn't a god.
艾耶斯先生是个大块头，但不是神
I have my god.
我有我的神
Mr. Steve Lopez.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生
Oh, boy.
噢，这下可好
Yeah, you're my god. Flying around high.
是啊，你是我的神，高高在上飞舞
- You're my god. - I'm not comfortable being your god.
- 你是我的神 - 做你的神让我不自在
Mr. Steve Lopez, staff writer, you are my god.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生，自由撰稿人 你是我的神
- That it? I'm your god? - Yes, you are. You're my god.
- 是吗？我是你的神？ - 是的，你是，你是我的神
All right. I am your god.
那好，我是你的神
And as your god,
而作为你的神
I command you to be at Lamp, 2:00 p.m., one week from today
我命令你，一周后，下午两点，到兰普来…
for a cello lesson. Done deal.
接受一堂大提琴课，说好了
And it's a really sweet deal, too.
而且这也是个甜美的约定
'Cause if you show up, I will grant you eternal life.
因为你来了，我会赐你永恒的生命
Hell, I might even make you a disciple.
该死，我甚至可能会让你成为我的门徒
If you don't, you're on your own.
如果你不来，我就要离开你了
This is my apartment. This is my apartment.
这是我的宿舍 这是我的宿舍
This is my apartment.
这是我的宿舍
Always number one. Always number two.
总是第1号，总是第2号
Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔
We've always been here, Nathaniel Ayers.
我们一直在你身边，纳杉尼尔・艾耶斯
I've always been with you, Nathaniel.
我一直陪伴着你，纳杉尼尔
I'll never leave you, Nathaniel. I love you, Nathaniel.
我永远不会离开你，纳杉尼尔 我爱你，纳杉尼尔
- I love you. - No one else loves you, Nathaniel.
- 我爱你 - 没有其他人爱着你，纳杉尼尔
But I love you, Nathaniel. I'll protect you, Nathaniel.
但我爱你，纳杉尼尔 我会保护你，纳杉尼尔
When you fell from Heaven, they laughed at you, Nathaniel.
当你从天堂坠落，他们都嘲笑你，纳杉尼尔
You're my heart, Nathaniel. I do love you, Nathaniel.
你是我的心，纳杉尼尔 我真的爱你，纳杉尼尔
We'll be together forever, Nathaniel.
我们会永远在一起，纳杉尼尔
I'll protect you.
我会保护你
Look, I'll be here to protect you from the pain.
看，我会在你身边保护你免受痛苦
- I'll be here to protect you from the pain. - Fibber. You fibber. You fib.
- 我会在你身边保护你免受痛苦 - 撒谎，你撒谎，撒谎
I'll protect you from the noise.
我会保护你远离这噪声
Fear for you. Fear for you.
害怕你，害怕你
I'll protect you from their beady eyes.
我会保护你远离他们的凶狠目光
- I'll be here to obey. - I'll protect you from their eyes.
- 我会对你唯命是从 - 我保护你不被他们看到
- Step right, Nathaniel. - No one else loves you, Nathaniel.
- 走对下一步，纳杉尼尔 - 没有其他人爱着你，纳杉尼尔
You're my boy, Nathaniel.
你是我的好孩子，纳杉尼尔
- Take off the shoes. - I'll protect you. I'll protect you.
- 脱鞋 - 我会保护你，我会保护你
No one can kill the child. That's what the child is about.
没人能杀死这孩子，因为这孩子是杀不死的
Forget you. Jump off!
忘了你，滚开！
Come on.
来吧
Hey. Look at that.
嘿，看看那牌子 （不准吸烟）
Don't see those on the street. Quick right.
没在街上看过这牌子，右转弯
And then, and then... And then right again, right here.
然后…然后…再右转，就在这
Nathaniel. Come on down.
纳杉尼尔，快来
What are you... Come on. We go down here and then to the end and left.
你在干…来吧 我们一直走到底然后左转
I think we should do the lesson out here.
我觉得我们应该在这外面上课
No, no, no. It's just this way. Come on.
不，不，不，就往这边走，来吧
Mr. Lopez... Mr. Lopez.
洛佩兹先生…洛佩兹先生
Mr. Lopez, I really think we should do it out here.
洛佩兹先生，我真觉得在这外面就好
No, come on. Let's have a look. It's right down here.
不，过来 过来看看，就在这边
Mr. Lopez.
洛佩兹先生
Nathaniel, come on.
纳杉尼尔，来吧
It's really clean.
里面很干净
Come check it out.
来看看就知道了
We should do it out here. It's better. I'm more comfortable out here.
我们应该在外面上课，这更好些 我在外面更自在些
Looks nice.
看起来不错
It's nice.
挺不错
Come on. You can do it.
来吧，你能做到的
Hey.
嘿
I can't live here.
我不能住在这
I'll give you a hand with that.
我来帮你搬
Got it.
好了
Oh, boy. Let's get this in nice.
噢，天，好好地把它弄进来
Good.
好
It's great, right?
挺棒，不是吗？
I mean, I like it. What do you think?
我说，我喜欢这，你觉得呢？
It's nice. It's clean. The bathroom's better than...
看起来不错，也干净，浴室还比…
Except for him.
除了这家伙
I don't wanna die in here.
我不想死在这里
Don't...
别…
Somebody could just come in here and kill me...
会有人直接走进来杀了我…
- You'll be fine. Nathaniel? ...and take all of my belongings.
- 你会没事的，纳杉尼尔 - …然后拿走我的东西
- Nathaniel, the door locks. - A fly only lives 12 days.
- 纳杉尼尔，这门能锁 - 一只苍蝇只能活12天
What if in 12 days, someone walks through that door and murders me?
如果12天之内，有人走进门然后杀了我呢？
And I don't care about this Claydon thing, either.
我不关心这克莱顿的事
Walt Disney Hall. Disney Duck.
华特・迪斯尼音乐厅，迪斯尼鸭
Doesn't make a difference. I don't need any of that.
这样没什么不同，我不需要这些
If I'm gonna take a lesson, I should take the lesson in the tunnel
如果我要上课，我就该在隧道里上课
where I can hear the city sounds and not be locked off from life,
那里我能听到这城市的声音 而不会与生活隔离
locked off from the world.
与这世界隔离
In the tunnel I can hear the music the way it's supposed to be played.
在隧道里我能听到音乐的本来面目
Not in this place, there's no city sounds,
而不是在这里，这里没有城市的声音
there's no Beethoven, there's no Los Angeles, California.
这里没有贝多芬 这里没有洛杉矶，加利福尼亚
I don't belong here.
我不属于这里
I'm never coming here again.
我不会再回这来了
Nathaniel, that's Graham Claydon.
纳杉尼尔，这是格拉汉・克莱顿
Pleased to meet you, Nathaniel.
见到你很愉快，纳杉尼尔
I always love meeting a fellow musician.
我一直喜欢和平民音乐家见面
I brought you something.
我给你带了样东西
I know you're partial to Beethoven,
我知道你很偏爱贝多芬
so I thought you'd enjoy this,
所以我觉得你会喜欢这个
because, you know, without Johann Sebastian
（巴赫的六部无伴奏大提琴组曲曲谱） 因为你知道，没有约翰・塞巴斯蒂安・巴赫
there would be no Ludwig van.
就没有后来的路德维奇・范・贝多芬 （贝多芬受巴赫影响很深）
The A, the D, the A, the D, the A, the D.
A弦，D弦，A弦，D弦，A弦，D弦
Steady. Don't rush it. Don't rush it.
稳住，别急，别急
And...
然后…
Well, for someone who hasn't had a lesson in three decades,
嗯，对于一个30年没再学琴的人来说
you play quite beautifully.
你拉得很漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢你
- So... - Thank you.
- 那么… - 谢谢你
Work on a smoother rhythm with the right hand.
右手多用些更柔和的旋律来练习
And don't stop-start.
还有不要让乐声间断
Carry a phrase all the way through.
乐句要整段地拉完
- Great. - Give you a ride uptown?
- 好极了 - 我送你进城吧
- Thank you. - Mr. Claydon?
- 谢谢你 - 克莱顿先生
- Yes. - Sir?
- 是的 - 先生？
Do you think I could be good again?
你觉得我还能像以前一样棒吗？
Yes, I do.
是的，我觉得
I like your apartment, by the way.
顺带一句，我喜欢你的宿舍
- It's not my apartment. - It's not. It's just a...
- 这不是我的宿舍 - 不是，这只是…
I don't live here.
我不住在这
Well, you should.
呃，你应该住下来
God has blessed you with a gift, Nathaniel.
上帝用异常的才赋祝福了你，纳杉尼尔
Nothing pains God more than when we squander his blessings.
没有比浪费他的祝福能让他更心痛的了
- You owe it to him to care for this... - I don't owe God.
- 为了回赠上帝你应该认真对待… - 我不欠上帝什么
Mr. Steve Lopez is my god.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生就是我的神
- What? - Star writer for Los Angeles.
- 什么？ - 洛杉矶的明星作家
Higher power flying around with wings like an angel.
有着更高强的力量 有着天使般的翅膀飞翔在上
Mr. Steve Lopez is my...
史蒂夫・洛佩兹就是我的…
He doesn't know what he's saying.
他不知道他在说什么
Mr. Graham Claydon is going to tell me who my god is?
格拉汉・克莱顿先生要告诉我谁是我的神？
Down by the car?
到我车那等我吧？
Do you know who my god is, Mr. Claydon?
知道我的神是谁吗，克莱顿先生？
I know who my god is!
我知道我的神是谁！
- He's a good teacher. - I know who my god is.
- 他是个好老师 - 我知道我的神是谁
You should accept his help gracefully.
你应该心存感激地接受他的帮助
Graceful is the ballerinas at Juilliard.
朱利亚德学校的芭蕾舞女才优雅 （心存感激和优雅同词）
Those girls were graceful.
那些姑娘就很优雅
- Tiny ballerinas just twirling round. - There's other people in this...
- 小巧的芭蕾舞女转了个圈 - 这周围还有其他人住…
- Twirling round. Angels. - All right,
- 转圈了，天使们 - 好吧
- graceful as little ballerinas. - I love them flying around
- 就像芭蕾舞女一样优雅 - 我喜欢天使在我身边飞舞
like I love Mr. Steve Lopez flying around.
就像我喜欢史蒂夫・洛佩兹先生在我身边 飞舞一样
I love God. I love you!
我爱神，我爱你！
I love you.
我爱你
I don't want him to love me.
我不想他爱我
Well, it looks like you might have to get over that.
嗯，看来你可能须要去习惯这样
It's a bad idea.
坏主意
"I love you, Steve," turns into, "You failed me, Steve,"
“我爱你史蒂夫”会变成 “你辜负我了史蒂夫”
turns into very bad things.
变成非常坏的事情
That's my limited experience.
我不愿经历这样的事
I don't want to be on the other side of that with him. Would you?
我不想当事情走到另一面的时候和他一起 你愿意这样？
He doesn't know if I'm a ballerina, if I'm God, if I'm an airplane pilot.
他根本不知道我是不是一个芭蕾舞女 我是不是个神，我是不是个飞行员
He has no idea what he's saying.
他根本不知道他在说什么
Is there something you want from me, Lopez?
你来找我有什么目的吗，洛佩兹？
Or did you just come to show me your prom dress? You look nice.
还是你只是来让我看你的舞会礼服？ 你看起来不错
I want you to help him
我要你帮助他
because he's sick and he needs medication
因为他有病，他需要治疗
and you have a team of doctors here.
而你这有整组的医生
Tell them to sit down with him. Isn't that what you're supposed to do?
让他们和他谈谈，这不是你们应该做的吗？
Nathaniel's made it quite clear he's not ready to speak to a psychiatrist.
纳杉尼尔说的很清楚了 他不准备见心理医生
Force him.
强迫他
- Force him? - Tell him to do it.
- 强迫他？ - 告诉他照做
Tell him he can't play his instruments
告诉他除非接受心理治疗
until he sits down with a shrink.
不然不能弹奏他的乐器
- That's not what we do here. - What you do here is fucked.
- 我们不干这样的事 - 你们干的事情就是胡扯
It is.
的确
Look, even if I did wanna cohorse Nathaniel into psychiatry...
听着 就算我想痹迫纳杉尼尔接受心理治疗
- Coerce. ...which... Whatever.
- 逼迫 - 这事…管它呢
- Coerce. - Lf I wanted to do that, which I don't,
- 逼迫 - 就算我想这么做，而我的确不想
I couldn't force him to take medication.
我也不能强迫他吃药
The law is the law. Unless he's an imminent danger
法律就是法律，除非他对自己或其他人…
to himself or someone else...
是个潜在的威胁
Are you gonna answer that, or what?
你到底要接电话还是怎样？
I'm in the car. What if he was a danger to someone else?
我在车里了 如果他对他人是个威胁呢？
- But he's not. - Mary, I'm on the way. Relax.
- 但他不是 - 玛丽，我在路上了，放松
What if someone said he was?
如果有人说他是呢？
What if someone dialed 911 and said Nathaniel had attacked him?
如果有人打911说纳杉尼尔攻击了他呢？
They'd put him in psychiatric hospital.
他们会把他送进精神病院
I know you're not thinking of lying on him, Lopez.
我知道你不会想要对他说谎，洛佩兹
And then he would be in a 14-day psychiatric hold,
然后他会被精神拘留14天
they'd put him on meds straight away.
他们就会直接给他用药
What if that's all it took for him to be well?
如果这样就能把他治好呢？
What if two weeks of meds, a two-week window
如果两周的药物治疗，一扇只需两周…
into what his life could be, changed his life? Saved his life?
就能让他过应有生活的明窗 就能改变他的生活，挽救他的生活呢？
Why wouldn't you want to be part of that?
为什么你不愿参与这样的行为？
Steve, Nathaniel has one thing going for him right now. A friend.
史蒂夫，纳杉尼尔的生命现在还剩一样东西 朋友
If you betray that friendship, you destroy the only thing he has in this world.
如果你背叛了这友谊 你就把他的生命给毁了
I don't want to be his only thing.
我不想做他生命里唯一的东西
Didn't you just tell somebody you was in your car?
你刚才不是和某人说你在车里吗？
Mary, relax. What table are we at?
玛丽，放松，你在哪张台？
This is Nathaniel Anthony Ayers, Jr., Mr. Lopez. I was calling...
我是纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世 洛佩兹先生，我打来…
- Nathaniel. ...because you promised me
- 纳杉尼尔 - …是因为你向我保证…
a hard case for my cello and I haven't received it yet.
会给我的大提琴带个硬箱子 但我还没收到
- Yeah? - And also I need sheet music
- 是吗？ - 而且我还需要…
for Beethoven's Second Sonata.
贝多芬第二奏鸣曲的谱纸
And also Opus 131 and Septet for strings and woodwinds, and Opus 20...
还有第131号作品和管弦七重奏的 还有20号…
Can you just... One sec.
你能不能…等等
...and also my A string is missing... - So, we're talking about...
- …还有我的A弦断了 - 那么，我们说的是…
I need my A string replaced.
我要更换我的A弦
Nathaniel, you know, this is not...
纳杉尼尔，知道吗，这不是…
... his series in the Times on the struggles and the triumphs
…他在洛杉矶时报上 关于纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯的…
of Nathaniel Anthony Ayers
奋斗和喜悦的系列报道…
has brought crucial attention to one of the most pressing issues in our city.
把人们的强烈关注 带到了本市最迫切的课题上
... promises you should make good on those promises...
…作了承诺你就该慎守那些承诺…
Get off the phone.
挂了电话
... to address this problem with compassion and commitment.
…带着同情和信诺去处理这个问题
And in honor of this,
为了对此表示敬意…
it is my pleasure to present this year's Media Award to Steve Lopez.
我很愉快地 将今年的媒体奖颁给史蒂夫・洛佩兹
Thank you.
多谢
... you know that I can't leave my cart anywhere.
…你知道我不能随便丢下我的手推车
It houses my violin, my cello, and my weapons of mass destruction.
它是我的小提琴、大提琴 和我大规模杀伤性武器的栖身之处
A child needs protection. You don't want to put a baby in the trunk of a car
一个孩子需要得到保护 你不会把一个婴儿放到车尾箱里…
and have it get bashed up against the wall.
然后把车撞到墙上
Bashed up against the wall. Bashed up against the wall.
撞到墙上，撞到墙上
I got a phone call from Mark Rosenthal today, remember him?
我今天接到一通来自马克・罗森萨尔的电话 还记得他吗？
Book editor?
图书编辑？
Bob Geldof with a crew cut.
就像剪了平头的鲍勃・杰道夫
He's been reading your Nathaniel stuff, thinks it's genius, whatever.
你一直在读你写的纳杉尼尔的文章 觉得很有才华，之类的
- Whatever. - Anyway. He said it's a book.
- 之类的？ - 总之，他说是个出书的好题材
What did he say exactly?
他怎么说的？
"It's personal, it's political, it's timely. I can sell the shit out of it."
“写人物、带政治、当下的 我能让这书他妈的热卖”
- Oh, boy. - His words, excuse me, not mine.
- 噢，天啊 - 他说的，抱歉，不是我
Well, it's complicated. Nathaniel's complicated.
其实，这很复杂，纳杉尼尔比较复杂
Well, yeah, he's mentally ill, I mean.
呃，是啊，他精神有毛病，我说
Right. But beyond that, it's endless.
是的，但这之外，他没法被写完
I just... I don't want to take full responsibility.
我只是…我不想负上全部责任
By all means, avoid full responsibility.
想方设法，避免负全责
Just, you know, keep going with the partial responsibility
你知道，只是一直担负着部分责任…
and exploiting him like you are now.
同时利用他，就像你现在做的
You should stop.
你该住嘴了
'Cause that's a slippery slope right there,
因为现在情况变得有些糟糕了
Lopez.
洛佩兹
- Stop. Stop. - One day, you're getting a book...
- 住嘴，别说了 - 有天有人给你写了本书…
- Please stop. ...from the guy. And the next,
- 请你别说了 - …然后那人…
he's expecting, I don't know, some sort of...
还期待着，怎么说来着…
Mary, stop.
玛丽，别说了
...consistency in the relationship. Screw that, man.
…重拾旧好，去他的吧，老兄
Who needs that shit, right? My words.
谁需要那狗屎，对吧？这我说的
- You driving? - No, I have a car.
- 你还开车吗？ - 不，但我有车
And a driver?
还有司机吧
- Oh, my God! - Oh, shit.
- 噢，我的天 - 噢，该死
It's Nathaniel for you.
纳杉尼尔找你的
... as a youngster labeled mentally ill
…一个年轻人被贴上精神异常的标签
because of the underlying cigarette habit,
因为他有形成烟瘾的潜在可能…
constant disturbance, constant disturbance.
以及持续的焦虑不安 持续的焦虑不安
You know, bigots have children, too.
你知道，偏执狂也有孩子
Pens from Steve Lopez. Many thanks.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹送的钢笔，非常感谢
Constant disturbance, constant disturbance.
持续的焦虑不安，持续的焦虑不安
Bigots have children. Bigots have children, too.
偏执狂有孩子，偏执狂也有孩子
Pens... Paper... Pens from Steve Lopez. Many thanks.
钢笔…纸… 史蒂夫・洛佩兹送的钢笔，非常感谢
And a cello from Steve Lopez. Steve Lopez... Many thanks to that.
史蒂夫・洛佩兹还送了大提琴 史蒂夫・洛佩兹…为此非常感谢
Without Steve Lopez, I wouldn't have any of that...
没有史蒂夫・洛佩兹，我永远得不到这些…
Constant disturbance.
持续的焦虑不安
Constant disturbance. Constant disturbances.
持续的焦虑不安 持续的焦虑不安
I've had what I think is a beautiful idea.
我有个我认为很棒的主意
I think Nathaniel should give a recital.
我觉得该为纳杉尼尔办场独奏会
I don't know if I can make that call. He hasn't been very lucid lately.
我不确定是否能让他这么做 他最近思维有些不清晰
- Right. When is he clearest? - I don't...
- 对啊，他什么时候最清醒？ - 我不…
When is he most able to focus his thoughts?
他什么时候最能集中思维？
- When he's playing. - Right.
- 就在他拉琴的时候 - 对
This could increase his confidence a thousand fold.
这样能极好地增加他的信心
It could be transformative.
他能因此而脱胎换骨
How can we not give him that, Steve?
我们怎能不给他这样的机会呢，史蒂夫？
God bless you, Steve.
愿上帝祝福你，史蒂夫
Sure he does.
当然他会
My first concert, I was so nervous, I vomited all down my tuxedo.
在我的第一次演出，我十分紧张 我吐了我的晚礼服一身
It was so embarrassing.
太让人难堪了
Want to know how I got over those jitters, Nathaniel?
想知道我怎么克服那些不安的吗 纳杉尼尔？
I prayed.
我祈祷
Shall we pray together, you and I?
我们一起祈祷好吗，你和我？
Heavenly Father,
天堂的天父啊
shine your light on brother Nathaniel,
让你的圣光照耀纳杉尼尔兄弟
that he may speak with your voice tonight.
让他今晚能奏出你的天籁
Nathaniel, you never have been here, Nathaniel. I'm here, Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔，你没有来过这 纳杉尼尔，我在这，纳杉尼尔
- You're not there. - Nathaniel.
- 你没在那边 - 纳杉尼尔
You never have been here. You never will be here.
你没来过这里，你不会来这里
My voice is all there is.
那边都是我的声音
Everything's fine.
一切安好
- Follow my voice, Nathaniel. - Tune up and play.
- 听从我的声音，纳杉尼尔 - 调好弦就开始
Run away from these people, Nathaniel.
从这些人这里跑开，纳杉尼尔
They'll laugh at you.
他们会嘲笑你
- You're nothing. - Nathaniel Ayers.
- 你什么也不是 - 纳杉尼尔・艾耶斯
Nathaniel?
纳杉尼尔？
I got some soup here for you.
我给你弄了些汤
You think I'm stupid. Is that what you think?
你觉得我很笨吗？那就是你的想法吗？
You want to kill them, Nathaniel. They'll kill you first, Nathaniel.
你想杀了他们，纳杉尼尔 他们会先杀了你，纳杉尼尔
No.
没
They'll string you up, Nathaniel.
他们会把你吊起来，纳杉尼尔
No. You think I can't see everything. I see everything.
不，你以为我看不到所有的事情 我能看到所有的事情
I know who you are. I know what you're doing.
我知道你是谁 我知道你在干什么
- Dogs, biting at your feet. - Nathaniel.
- 一群狗，在撕咬你的脚 - 纳杉尼尔
- I thought you might be hungry. - Nathaniel, over there.
- 我想你饿了 - 纳杉尼尔，在那
- The dusty open manual. - Nathaniel, come here.
- 肮脏、开放的手把 - 纳杉尼尔，来这
The manual.
手把
That's hydrochloric acid. If I eat that, it'll burn me up inside and kill me like a dog.
这是盐酸，如果是吃下它 它会在里面像杀死一条狗一样地烧死我
- Oh, no. - Nathaniel.
- 噢，不会 - 纳杉尼尔
- Nathaniel, I wouldn't do that. - Nathaniel.
- 纳杉尼尔，我不会这么做 - 纳杉尼尔
Nathaniel.
纳杉尼尔
You'll eat it, dust and all.
你会吃下它，连同灰尘，全部
Okay.
好的
It's good, see.
很好吃，看到了吗？
Shit.
该死
Don't put your hands on me!
别用你的手摸我
- Nathaniel! - Back the hell off!
- 纳杉尼尔！ - 给我滚开！
Don't you ever touch me! Don't ever put your hands on me!
永远别再碰我！ 永远别再用你的手碰我！
Please, don't. Nathaniel.
请别这样，纳杉尼尔
Don't you ever touch me.
永远别再碰我
Stop.
住手
Nathaniel!
纳杉尼尔！
What am I supposed to do? I should have support.
我该怎么做？ 我该找人帮忙
Hi, Nathaniel.
嗨，纳杉尼尔
It's freezing out here. Don't you wanna come home?
这外面真冷，你不想回家吗？
I can't go back there. It's not safe.
我不能回去，那不安全
Come on, home, Nathaniel.
回家吧，纳杉尼尔
Nathaniel?
纳杉尼尔？
Where are you gonna sleep?
你要到哪儿去睡觉？
David, sorry, it's Steve. Listen.
大卫，抱歉，我是史蒂夫，听着
Can you call me back when you have a second?
你有空的时候能不能给我回电？
There was an incident with Nathaniel tonight. I'm a little
今晚纳杉尼尔发生了一件意外 我有点…
worried. Anyway, call back when you have a sec.
担心 总之，有空的时候给我回电
All right, let's go.
好了，走吧
It's my thing! I claim my right to those possessions!
这是我的！ 我对这些财产声明所有权！
Show me your stuff!
让我看看你的本事！
- Linda! - What?
- 琳达！ - 什么事？
- Hey, where's Nathaniel? - I don't know. I haven't seen him.
- 嘿，纳杉尼尔在哪儿？ - 不知道，我没见到他
- I haven't seen him. - Hey! Hey!
- 没见到他 - 嘿！嘿！
Is it Darryl?
是达瑞尔吗？
Hey, stay back. Who the hell are you?
嘿，后退，你是那根葱？
LA Times. That's the last guy you should be arresting.
洛杉矶时报的，这是你最不该抓的人
- Come on, man! Come on. - Skid row cleanup, sir. Let's go.
- 别这样，老兄！别这样 - 贫民窟清理，先生，走吧
Steve! Steve!
史蒂夫！史蒂夫！
This man is in illegal possession of a shopping cart and a milk crate.
这人非法占有一个购物手推车和一个牛奶箱
Are you gonna arrest him for possession of a milk crate?
你逮捕这人就为了他占有一个牛奶箱？
- Steve! Steve! - That's correct, sir.
- 史蒂夫！史蒂夫！ - 没错，先生
Take it easy.
放松点
Help! Help!
救命！救命！
Come on!
快走！
Officer, what happened?
警官，怎么回事？
A couple of kids came out here with some baseball bats
有几个孩子带着棒球棒到这来
and beat the shit out of this poor guy.
把这可怜家伙打得够惨
- Get a name? - Negative, sir.
- 知道名字吗？ - 不，先生
Sorry, excuse me. I'm sorry.
抱歉，抱歉，我很抱歉
Is this Admits? May I make an enquiry about a... Excuse me.
接待处？我想询问一下…抱歉
- This way? - What?
- 这边走？ - 什么？
Yeah, down here.
是的，就在那
It's usually on the... I'm sorry. It's usually on the screen.
平时我在…抱歉 平时我在屏幕上就能看到
Excuse me, ma'am. Recent ER admits named Ayers, A-Y-E-R-S.
劳驾，女士 新进急诊，登记名字“艾耶斯”，A-Y-E-R-S
Thank you, by the way.
对了，谢谢
No.
没
Hi. Thank you.
嗨，多谢
I'm looking for a recent admission.
我在找一个新进人员
I'm hoping you have a recent admission with a man named Ayers, A-Y-E-R-S.
我希望你这有一个叫艾耶斯的新进人员 A-Y-E-R-S
I know. Contreras was the reporting officer. He was the officer on site.
我知道，康特雷拉斯是值班人员 他就在场
It's not the... It's not the...
这不是…这不是…
Mr. Ayers. A-Y-E-R-S.
艾耶斯先生，A-Y-E-R-S
Nathaniel Anthony Ayers. 5'10" African-American.
纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯 5尺10寸，非裔美国人
Hi. It's me again.
嗨，还是我
It's gonna be a long shift. What's your name?
这轮夜班会很长的，你叫什么名字？
N-A-T-H-A-N-l-E-L A...
N-A-T-H-A-N-I-E-L A…
I do words for a living. It doesn't matter.
我以写作谋生，这没有关系
Whoever has two stripes on their arm or more.
不论谁手臂有两条或以上线痕
Ayers! A-Y-E-R-S.
艾耶斯！A-Y-E-R-S
N-A-T-H-A-N-l-E-L A-N-T-H-O-N-Y A-Y-E-R-S.
N-A-T-H-A-N-I-E-L A-N-T-H-O-N-Y A-Y-E-R-S
No! Do not put me on hold again!
不！别再挂起我的电话！
A-Y-E-R-S!
A-Y-E-R-S！
- Lopez. - Steve, David.
- 我是洛佩兹 - 史蒂夫，我是大卫
I got your message, what's up?
我收到你的消息了，怎么了？
There was a beating of a homeless man on Winston Street,
昨晚有人在温斯顿大街殴打流浪者
- it was right in Nathaniel's spot. - It wasn't him.
- 就在纳杉尼尔的那块地方 - 不是他
What? How do you know?
什么？你怎么知道？
'Cause he's here, eating a crazy-big breakfast.
因为他就在这，吃着一份特大早餐
I guess sleeping inside can give a man an appetite.
我猜睡在里面能让一个人好胃口
What?
什么？
He spent last night in the apartment.
他昨晚整晚都在那间宿舍里
He came inside.
他住进去了
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you so much.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢 谢谢，太谢谢你了
I thought I lost it forever.
我以为我永远失去它了
Hi.
嗨
You good?
你还好吧？
I literally looked everywhere else in Los Angeles but here.
我几乎找遍了洛杉矶的所有地方 除了这里
Not that I was worried.
不是因为我担心
What happened? What made you decide to sleep in here?
发生了什么事？ 是什么让你决定睡进来了？
Oh, well, a body can only take so much, Mr. Lopez.
噢，呃，一个人只能承受那么多了 洛佩兹先生
I'm not young anymore, I'm a middle-aged man.
我已经不年轻了，我是一个中年男人了
- You know how it is. - Sure.
- 你知道是怎样的 - 当然
I mean, a body gets weary, a body...
我的意思是，一个人会疲倦，一个人…
Housewarming gift.
新屋入伙礼物
Thank you, Mr. Lopez.
谢谢，洛佩兹先生
Thank you, Mr. Lopez. Thank you.
谢谢，洛佩兹先生，谢谢
I've done good by you, haven't I?
我一直对你很好，不是吗？
I mean, things aren't so bad, right?
我说，事情并不坏，不是吗？
Say, things are set for Jennifer to become your executor.
话说，他们安排好让詹妮弗作你的执行人
I can't believe Beethoven himself is in my own apartment.
不敢相信贝多芬本人就在我的宿舍里
Are you still okay with that? Having Jennifer handle things for you?
让詹妮弗帮你处理事情，你觉得没问题吧？
It's all right with me if it's all right with Beethoven.
如果贝多芬没问题，我也没问题
Well, you guys let me know.
那么，你们俩说好了告诉我
'Cause there's papers you gotta sign. They just got back from...
因为这些文件需要你签名，刚到的
You should read them so you know what you're signing.
你应该先读读它们，好知道你在签什么
All right, yeah, I'll just sign them Nathaniel Anthony Ayers, Jr.,
好的，好 我就签上纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世
apartment B-116, and the B stands for
住址：B-116宿舍，而B就是…
Beethoven.
贝多芬
- Read them and sign them. - All right.
- 先读后签 - 好的
- Okay. - All right.
- 好 - 好的
What do you... You got anything to drink?
你有…你有什么喝的吗？
Yes, sir, Mr. Lopez. Absolutely, Mr. Lopez,
是的，先生，洛佩兹先生 当然有，洛佩兹先生
help yourself to some water, it's where the dripping sound is coming from.
请随便喝些水，就在那滴水声的源头
- At your leisure. - All right.
- 你就躺着吧 - 好的
Is there a...
那有…
What's with Neil Diamond?
这尼尔・戴尔蒙德是怎么回事？ （他是位歌手兼音乐创作人）
I thought that was you.
我以为那是你
Well, I'm flattered. He's a good-Iooking guy.
呃，我受宠若惊，他挺帅的
What's wrong?
怎么了？
What's this business about me
这是怎么一回事？
having a schizophrenic mind?
说我有精神分裂？
It's, it's... It's legal jargon.
这只是…只是法律用语
It says that I have a schizophrenic mind. I do not.
它说我有精神分裂症 我没有
It doesn't mean anything.
这不代表任何事情
- I have a schizophrenic mind. - That's not what I think.
- 我有精神分裂症 - 我不这么认为
Nathaniel, they try to put people in a...
纳杉尼尔，他们努力把人们…
- I'm not going anywhere. - And the good news is that
- 我哪儿也不去 - 而好消息就是…
it has nothing to do with you.
这份东西和你没关系
I don't go where you say to go. I go where I want to go.
我不去你要我去的地方 我只去我想去的地方
You don't put me away, Mr. Lopez. You don't put me away.
你不能把我踢开，洛佩兹先生 你不能把我一脚踢开
- Okay. Okay. - You don't put me away.
- 好，好 - 你不能把我踢开
I'm not gonna... I don't...
我不会…我不会
- No, no, you don't have to go... - Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
- 不，不，不，你不需要… - 是的，你是，是的，你是
...to court. You don't have to go anywhere.
…去法庭，你哪儿也不用去
Jennifer will take care of you.
詹妮弗会照顾好你的
My sister's not coming near me. She is not coming near me.
我妹妹不愿意接近我，她不会接近我
- She's not coming near me. - Okay, remember when you said...
- 她不会接近我 - 那好，还记得你说过…
If I say she's not coming then she's not coming.
如果我说她不会来，她就不会来
You said... Nathaniel, you said...
你说过…纳杉尼尔，你说过…
Listen, I'm not going to have anymore... I'm not going to have anymore...
听着，我不会再忍受下去了… 我不会再忍受下去了…
I will tell you. I will tell you. I'm sick of being Nathaniel and you Mr. Lopez.
我告诉你，我告诉你，我已经厌烦 去做洛佩兹先生的伙伴纳杉尼尔了
Okay. I'm not just...
好，我不是…
Wait. I'm not your boy. I am not Mr. Colonel Sanders's boy.
等等，我不是你的孩子 我不是桑德斯上校的孩子
You know, I'm sorry I was wrong. I'm sorry I was wrong.
知道吗，我很抱歉我做错了 我很抱歉我做错了
I can take care of myself. I can take care of myself, Mr. Lopez.
我能照顾好我自己 我能照顾好我自己，洛佩兹先生
I don't need you. I don't need this city. I despise this city and I despise you.
我不需要你，我不需要这城市 我蔑视这城市我蔑视你
And if I ever see you again,
如果我再看到你
I'll cut you open
我会给你开膛破肚
and gut you like a fish.
就像切一条鱼一样
Because I'm Nathaniel Anthony Ayers Jr.
因为我是纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世
Mr. Ayers.
艾耶斯先生
I'm Nathaniel Anthony Ayers Jr. N-A-T-H-A...
我是纳杉尼尔・安东尼・艾耶斯二世 N-A-T-H-A…
N-A-T-H-A...
N-A-T-H-A…
- N-A-T-H-A... - You're of no consequence.
- N-A-T-H-A… - 你无足轻重
- Hi. - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
So, that was my first mistake.
那就是我的第一个错误
The Northridge Quake, '94, remember?
94年的北岭地震，还记得吗？
I smelled the toast.
我闻到了土司味
We'd been here two days.
当时我们刚到这两天
All our crap still in boxes.
我们的破烂还在箱子里
And at 4:00 a.m. It hit.
然后在凌晨4点，地震了
God, that terror.
天，恐怖
You, me and Thomas. What was he, nine?
你、我还有托马斯，他那时多大？9岁？
All huddled under that bedroom door frame.
都蜷缩在卧室的门框边
I told him it was a good omen.
我和他说这是个…
Welcoming us to our new life.
迎接我们新生活的好兆头
Better life.
更好的生活
In LA.
洛杉矶的生活
I should have had us on the first flight back to Philly.
我当时就该让我们坐上回费城的第一班机
I thought I was helping someone.
我以为我在帮助某人
And it was a guy who's got a gift.
而那是个有天赋的人
He's lost his way. I'm gonna...
他迷失了方向，我想…
Inevitably backfired.
不可避免的反作用
He's backlashed to the...
他又回到了…
And the very person I was trying to be of some redeeming service to turns on me.
我努力想给他些类似补偿的帮助 而那个人却与我对峙
I'm the enemy. You know?
我成了他的敌人，知道吗？
A stranger.
好像陌生人
And...
而且…
I don't know who to fault.
我不知道该归咎于谁
I can't see any outcome to support.
我完全看不到让我支撑下去的结果
Can't believe in anything worthwhile.
也相信不了任何值得坚持的理由
Done trying. I resign. I resign.
尝试结束了，我不干了，不干了
From everything.
什么事也不干了
It's... It's official.
这是…这是正式的
You couldn't stop that earthquake.
你阻止不了那场地震
You can't fix LA in just...
你无法靠这个把洛杉矶变成天堂
And you're never gonna cure Nathaniel.
而且你永远治不好纳杉尼尔
Just be his friend and show up.
作他的朋友，去看望他，就足够了
Good? I'll be right here if you need me.
能行吧？如果需要我我就在这边
...go, next to the gold store.
…走，就在金铺下面
You know what I mean. He wanted to drink and everything.
知道我的意思吗？ 他想喝酒，还想做所有事情
Okay, okay, okay. Bitch, slow down.
好了，好了，好了 婆娘，慢些讲
Do you still love me? Like you did at the start?
你还爱我吗？就像你当初那样？
I ain't playing with you.
我不是在和你耍
I'm saying I do.
我要说我愿意
It means you and me together forever.
这意味着你和我永远在一起
So that's why I'm saying I do.
所以我说我愿意
- I love you, Lois. - I love you, too, Darryl.
- 我爱你露易丝 - 我也爱你，达瑞尔
Disguise himself now as...
现在他假装他好像…
They disguise themselves... Where is Los Angeles?
他们都在假装… 洛杉矶在哪儿？
Cleveland?
克里夫兰？
And...
而且…
We...
我们…
We had some life, didn't we?
我们有过不错的生活，不是吗？
Yeah.
是的
Beethoven's Triple Concerto, right?
贝多芬的三重协奏曲，是吧？
- Yeah. - It's a good one.
- 是的 - 不错的作品
I liked it.
我喜欢
Mr. Ayers, I'm gonna give your sister a ride to the hotel.
艾耶斯先生，我要开车把你妹妹送到酒店去
You don't have to call me that, Mr. Lopez.
你不必这样称呼我，洛佩兹先生
I know. I want to. I should have been calling you that all along.
我知道，我想这样 我应该从开始就一直这样叫你
I said such terrible things to you, Mr. Lopez.
我对你说了些可怕的话，洛佩兹先生
I... I hate myself for saying those things.
我…我恨我自己说过那些话
Sometimes friends piss each other off, right?
有时候朋友也会互相惹火对方，不是吗？
It's part of the deal.
这也是约定的一部分
I can't imagine that you would want to be my friend after I said all those things.
我无法想象在我说过那些话之后 你还想作我的朋友
I just...
我只是…
Mr. Ayers,
艾耶斯先生
I'm honored to be your friend.
我很荣幸能作你的朋友
"Points West" by Steve Lopez.
“指向西部”，史蒂夫・洛佩兹著
A year ago, I met a man who was down on his luck
一年前，我遇见一位处于低谷的人
and thought I might be able to help him.
而我觉得我或许能帮助他
I don't know that I have.
我不知道我做到了
Yes, my friend Mr. Ayers now sleeps inside.
是的，我的朋友艾耶斯先生现在不再露宿了
He has a key. He has a bed.
他有把钥匙，他有张床
But his mental state, and his well-being,
但他现在的精神和状态…
are as precarious now as they were the day we met.
就和我们相遇那天一样的时好时坏
There are people who tell me I've helped him.
有人告诉我，我已经帮了他忙
Mental health experts who say
精神专家说…
that the simple act of being someone's friend can change his brain chemistry,
作朋友这个简单的举措 就可以改变他脑中的化学物质
improve his functioning in the world.
就能让他在这世上活得更好些
I can't speak for Mr. Ayers in that regard.
我不能代替艾耶斯先生说这样的话
Maybe our friendship has helped him. But maybe not.
或许我们的友谊帮助了他，或许没有
I can, however, speak for myself.
无论如何，我能代表我自己说…
I can tell you that by witnessing Mr. Ayers's courage,
在见证过艾耶斯先生的技艺中…
his humility, his faith in the power of his art,
所展现的勇气、谦逊和信仰之后…
I've learned the dignity of being loyal to something you believe in.
我了解了一个人那忠于自身信仰…
Of holding onto it, above all else.
那心无旁骛地坚持不懈…
Of believing, without question, that it will carry you home.
那毫无疑问的坚信中，所表现出的高贵 而这，就能让你找到归宿